Okay, good evening everyone. Welcome to today's seminar
session. My name is Latapum Palichatwisha
from Kimmukud Institute of Technology, Latkabang, the
co-host of this hackathon. And I will be your
moderator today. Before we begin, a quick look at our
schedule. Our speakers represent for 45 minutes,
which will be followed by 15 Q&A session. If you have
questions during the presentation, please feel
free to drop them in the chat box. We will
address them at the end of the conversation.
Or you can raise your hand and I will start. We will tell
you. We will let you ask the question,
the short question to the lecture speaker. Tonight, we have
two experts in the corporate AI
visionary and AI strategies with proven the tech records.
It is now my absolute pressure
to introduce today's first speaker, Dr. Wuran-yoo Su-ji,
Wala Panpong. Dr. Wuran-yoo or Dr. Yoo
is a founder and CEO of the limited ICT, a leading Google
Cloud premier partner in Thailand.
Sub-specializing in cloud transformation, AI solutions and
expertise in technology implementation.
He has extensive experience in expertise
in IT strategy, digital transformation,
helping number us scale up and
implementation projects across Thailand.
His expertise includes AI adoption, cloud technology,
enterprise systems and technology drive and business
innovation. Today, he will be presenting
on the topic, engineering AI across the border, building AI
for real world global challenge.
Please join me in giving a warm welcome to Dr. Wuran-yoo
and Dr. Wuran-yoo, the floor is yours.
Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Good evening and thanks Professor
Panpong. And okay. So yeah. Yeah.
I'm yeah. Let me have a look at the kind of chat. Yeah.
This is because I'm not quite
your family with soon because we have been working with
Google for many years. So I'm
yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. I found the, okay. Yeah. Okay. The,
yeah, what I'm going to talk in the next
45 minutes is about engineering AI. Yeah. Across the
borders, because I know that most of you
attending are participating in the UN Global hackathon. So
yeah, today I would like to share
the experience about, you know, yeah, what we should
prepare, you know, if you would like to
expand your AI solutions or AI project. Yeah. Across the
borders. Yeah. Yeah. And then, and then
the key question today is, it's not how we build the AI,
but the question is, how do we build AI
system that create the real world
impact across different countries, cultures,
regulations, and communities? Yeah. Yeah.
That is what we will explore together today.
And first of all, I would like to introduce about, about
myself. Yeah. As, as, as, yeah, professor
at the boom, you have mentioned, yeah, I'm from the middle
ICT. I'm, I'm the father and CEO of
the company. We have been working with Google for, for 10
years. We are the partner of, of
Google cloud solutions in Asia Pacific. And not only
Google, we also yeah, collaborating with
other solutions as well. And then most of the solutions
we'll, yeah, react with the AI. And
at the moment, we are serving more than 4,600 business
customers in 14 countries. Our headquarters
is in Bangkok. We are, we have the, the subsidiaries in
Singapore and in, and in China as well. Okay.
Okay. Yeah. This is a brief introduction and, and the topic
today, okay. That, that I, I know that
most of you are interested in the hackathon. And then I
believe all of you will be really keen to,
to think about, you know, think about AI. But today I am
going to share you some, some aspects,
about the AI project that if you like to do, yeah, across
the borders and you then can prepare your,
your project to win the mic of, of the judges for this
project. Okay. And, and, and first of all,
I would like to, to, yeah, I think that you know that,
yeah, we are living through one of the
fastest technology adoption cycles in the human history.
Yeah. Millions of, of AI projects are
being developed. Thousands of AI startups are being funded.
Billions of dollars are being invested
every week. You know, we have a new model, a new favorite,
a new AI company, a new breakthrough.
The amount of innovation happening right now is incredible.
And yet, yeah, something interesting
is happening. Yeah. Despite all, all these activities, most
AI projects never create meaningful
impact. The technology is advancing rapidly, but the real
world, your adoption and measurable value
are not going at the same rate. Yeah. Why is that? That is
the question that we would like to start
discussion today. Okay. Yeah. First of all, I would like, I
have a really simple question. Yeah. To ask
you. Okay. Actually I have the, I have the poll. Yeah.
Yeah. That, that I, I, that I would like to,
to know that I read to hear from, hear from you guys as
well. Okay. And first of all,
this is a QR code. Okay. If you have your mobile phone with
you, you can pick your mobile phone and
then scan this QR code. And then the first
question I would like to, to, to learn from
you also, how many AI prototype have you built before?
Yeah. Never. Yeah. One, two, three, four,
two, 10 or more than 10. Okay. Yeah. Okay.
Yeah. Okay. That is, it sounds, oh, some,
some participants are really expert. Yeah. More than, more
than 10 prototypes. Okay. Okay. Yeah.
Yeah. Okay. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. For example. Yeah.
Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. Okay. How, how,
how many participants do we have? Okay. Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
This is a very simple question. So,
yeah, let's assume that we have it, it, it guys response to
these first questions. It means
about 50% of the participants here have experiences in
doing AI prototype. Yeah. This is the first one.
And then the second questions before I move forward is how
many are currently used by the
real users? By the real users? Not, not your, not yourself,
but just by others, your parents,
your friends, or whoever. Oh yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Some, some
participants, okay, have experiences
using with a, yeah, deploy in the real development with the
real users. Yeah. Yeah. But of course,
you know, yeah. Yeah. Some of you may, may be newbie in
the, yeah. Yeah. In this area, but, but you,
at least you, you know how to build the AI prototype
before, but, but, but just lack of the
experience to, to deploy for, for, for, for the real users.
Okay. Yeah. That's why I, I, I, I, I,
I would like to, to, to talk about this today. So yeah.
Okay. This, yeah. What you answer me,
yeah. This happens everywhere, you know, in the university,
startups, government, the large,
enterprise. Yeah. Yeah. We build a prototype in, in common,
you know, creating, but however, you know,
we, but when we come to talk about the impact, yeah, that
is the big questions that how can we,
how can they build the prototype that create the impact
that other users can use? Okay. And this is,
and another fact that is a thousand of ideas become
prototypes, but from the statistic,
some, some prototypes, yeah, becomes
pilot. However, much smaller number reach the
applications and only probably, you know, one or 2%, a
handful created the meaningful impact.
The challenges, the challenge is not building something
that works once, but the challenge,
but the challenge for everyone participating in this
program is how to build something that
survive the really, you have to, how to get the users, how
to get the real organizations,
the real, the real constraints, the real regulations, the
real expectations. This is why I often
always say that reading a demo is easy, you know, but the
most difficult part is to create
the impact is quite hard. Okay. And
let's take this idea one step further. Okay.
Most teams start at the prototype stage. They prove that
the technology works and then the project
ends, but a prototype is not a destination. It is only the
beginning, yeah. To create the value,
a prototype must have and must become an application and
the application must become a
production system. And only then it creates the real world
impact. Many people think success
happens when the models work, but the fact is the success
happens when the people use it
consistently and benefit from it. So this is one of the
biggest misconceptions in AI that
the success comes from having a better model. Yeah. Of
course, you know, yeah, models matter,
but let me ask a few questions. What happens if the model
is excellent, but the data is poor?
What happens if the users do not touch it? What happens if
it doesn't fit into their workflow?
What happens if nobody adopts it? A
great model alone doesn't create the value.
AI success is the combination of many factors. The problem
being solved, the quality of the data,
the workflow, the people, the governance. The technology is
only one piece of a much larger
system. And after working in technology projects for many
years, I have noticed the same patterns
repeatedly. The project fails because they solve problems
nobody actually has. Yeah. So it means no
real problems. And project fails because the data is poor.
The project fails because they do not fit
into existing workforce. The project fails because users do
not touch them. And the project
fails because nobody owns them after the deployment. Yeah.
Notice something important. Very few projects
fail because the model is not smart enough. Most failures
are the human failures, organizational
failures, operational failures, not the AI failures. And
that is why how to engineering it.
It is a matter of how can you make the AI project success.
And this is one of the most important
slides in the M-type presentations. When people talk about
the AI, they often think about the
technologies, models, tools, infrastructures. But that is a
missing layer between technologies
and impact, which is people. Yeah.
People decide whether they trust the system.
People decide whether they adopt it. People decide whether
it changes the behavior. People decide
whether it creates value. Technology by itself doesn't
change the world. People change the world
using the technologies. And that
is why understanding human adoption
is just as important as understanding the AI.
Okay. And so far, we have learned
several important lessons. Most AI projects
doesn't reach impact. Most teams stop at prototype. Most
failures are not technical failures.
And successful AI requires much more than models, which
leads us to the next questions.
Okay. If building AI is not enough, what does it actually
take to build AI across the borders?
Because once we move beyond a single organization, a single
language, or a single country,
the complexity increases dramatically. Let's explore the
next. So far, we have discussed
why many AI projects fail. And now let's
talk about what happens when we implement AI
across the borders. When organizations first expand
internationally, the language is usually
the first challenge they notice. But
language is often the easiest problem to solve.
Modern AI models are already remarkably good at
translation. Yet, many AI projects still fail
internationally. Why? This is because translation doesn't
solve cultural differences. It doesn't
solve regulatory differences. And it certainly doesn't
solve organization capacities.
So when I think about the cross-border AI, I do not think
about one border. I think about
multiple borders. Language, cultures, regulations,
infrastructure, organizations,
and most AI discussions focus on language. But in
real-world departments, the other borders are
often more difficult. Let's explore them one by one. The
first one is the language. Language is
more than words. Language carries meaning, context, intent,
emotion, industry-specific terminology,
legal terminology. Even the simple phrases can have very
different interpretations in different
countries. Translation is important, but understanding
context is far more important.
The second one is culture. Culture influences expectations.
Imagine the same customers service
AI deploy globally, and American customers may prioritize
the speed. The Japanese customers may
prioritize politeness. The German customers may prioritize
transparency. The Thai customers may
prefer human assistance when situations become complex. The
model may be identical, but the
expectations are not. And the expectations
determine user adoptions. The next one is
regulations. Regulations are very significant across the
countries. We have different rules,
we have different compliance requirements, we have
different privacy standards, different approaches
to data governance. A system that works perfectly in one
country may require a major redesign in
another. This is why compliance cannot be an afterthought.
It must be a part of the architecture
from the beginning. Not every region has the same
infrastructure, not every organization also has
the same resources. They may have different cloud
environments, different connectivity, different
devices, different operational
constraints. Engineering AI for the global deployment
requires adapting to the reality. Technology must work in
the environment where people actually
live and work. When we talk about
the organizations, this is the border
many technical teams underestimate.
Different stakeholders often have different goals.
Engineering wants innovations,
for example. Operations wants
real-life abilities. The legal team may want to risk their
reductions. The business wants
growth. Everyone has their own value priorities, but
alignment becomes difficult. So many AI projects
fail because organizations are not
aligned, but because the technology is inadequate.
So let's pause for a moment. We have discussed five
different borders, the language, the cultures,
the languages, infrastructure, and organizations. Now
imagine something simple. Imagine deploying
exactly the same AI system in four different countries, the
same model, the same architecture,
the same code. Everything is identical. Yet the results may
be completely different. Why? Because
the users are different. Everything is different.
Organization, regulations, expectations are
different. Technology stays the same. The context changes.
That changes when we would like to
deploy the same technology, the same model to another
places. So this is the second one.
Okay. This is the second part. Most
people may not think about it. The second is,
what do you think? Okay. Let me try. What do you think is
the biggest challenge in the cross-border
AI? Yeah. Let you, yeah. Just like to hear from you also,
you know, language, cultures,
equations, infrastructures, or organizations. Okay. Yeah.
Your language, yeah. Your language is,
okay. Okay. This is great organizations.
Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
That is the, okay. Let's wait for another two. Okay. Yeah.
Yeah. I think, okay. Yeah. Yeah.
Let's wait for another one. Okay. Yeah. Actually, I asked
these questions in many events also.
Yeah. Yeah. Some events, they think that, oh, language is
probably the biggest challenge.
But it depends, you know. But the fact is, yeah,
declaration is definitely one of the biggest
challenges. But actually, this question has no right or
wrong answers. It depends on the situations.
But I just would like to remind you that, you know, not
only, you know, doing the cross-border AI,
you know, not, not, not the language is, is only one of the
factors. But yeah, for example,
yeah. Yeah. Yeah. We have experiences in implementing the
system in, yeah, in, in China,
in fast factors, and the creation is, is one of the, is two
of the most headaches things. Yeah. Yeah.
Because for example, how we keep the data or about the,
that infrastructure also. Yeah. Yeah. Because
when we implement the project, the project in China, yeah,
that is a kind of the, yeah, great, great.
We call it as, yeah, great firewall that, that, that, that
it is difficult for, for the users in
China to, to access the system outside China. Yeah. Yeah.
This is, this is one of the key things.
Okay. Thanks for the second, for the
second post. And I want to, to move next is,
okay. The real examples, let's, let, let me give you the
practical examples. Imagine that we build
the customers, support AI assistant. The AI is successfully
in one country, customer like it,
the business like it, if everything works well. Now we
decide to deploy exactly the same solutions
globally. Yeah. At first glance, it seems that easy
technology, everything's, yeah, that go well.
Yeah. First. Okay. So what, so the, the question is what
could go wrong? Okay. First the, the language
changes. Yeah. Yeah. This is, I understand that. Do you
understand that when the language change,
the translation must be accurate, the terminology differs.
So you have to be careful on this.
And then the second is the language change. Different
countries have different privacy law,
different compliance requirements, different rules
regarding the data storage and usage.
And the expectation also changed. Yeah. Yeah. From the
cultures. Yeah. As I mentioned, some
prioritize the speed, some prioritize the
politeness, some prefer the self-service,
some prefer the speaking to the human and
eventually all of these factors affect the
outcomes. The technology is identical, but the basics
result are not. Yeah. This is why the
scaling AI is not simple copying the technologies, but we
have to consider all of these factors as
well. Okay. Yeah. Let me give you one, one example that I
always talk with my students. Yeah. Let's,
let me give you a practical examples. This is considered
the Netflix, right? Netflix uses AI
globally, but the recommendations are not identical
everywhere. The users preference differ, viewing
viewing behavior differs, languages differ, local
regulations differ, the same AI platform
operates across many markets, but the implementation adapts
to the local context. This is an important
lessons. The step technology can produce very different
outcomes depending on where it is
deployed. Yeah. This is the examples of Netflix. Okay.
Yeah. Because Netflix, if you have an
opportunity to see the content or the
recommendation, it varies. Okay. And then
most people, or at least say the models, this is the
visible part, but beneath the surface,
like everything else, you know, data, the governance,
operations, compliance, localizations,
people's. Yeah. These are often the factors that determine
success or failures. The model
receive the attentions, the invisible layers create the
impact. Yeah. That's why let's bring
everything together. So far we have discussed five
different models, as I mentioned, but if you
remember only one framework from this section, I would like
to be this one. The engineering AI
across the borders is not just about the building a model.
It requires us to think about five
dimensions. The first one, the first one is a problem. Are
we solving a real problem that
people actually care about? A great model, solving the
wrong problem creates no value. This is the
first one. The second is the people. View user has it. View
they adopt it. View they change behavior
without adoption. There is no impact. The third is a
process. How does AI fit into the existing
workflow? Does it reduce frictions or does it create
additional works? And the platform,
definitely do we have the right data, the right
architectures, the right infrastructures. Yeah,
technology matters, but the technology alone is not enough.
And the last one is a policy. Can the
solutions comply with the regulations? Can it be govern or
task at scale? And when all five dimensions
work together, AI creates the values. When one dimension is
missing, the project will be stuck.
So before we move into the architectures and the system
design, I would like to leave you with a
simple checklist. We think you evaluate an idea, start up a
project or even a hackathon concept
ask these five questions. Can a user task it? Yeah, because
if people do not task a system,
they will not use it. Can it scale? Because solving a
problem for 10 users is very different
from solving it for 10 million users. Can it comply?
Because every department operates within
regulatory and organizational constraints. Can people adopt
it? Because a technical billion
solutions that nobody uses create no values. And finally,
can it survive? Yeah, can it survive
the bad data and expected
behavior, organizational policy? Yeah. And
so far, we have explored why AI
project fails because they may not consider
all things that I just mentioned. The next question is,
what does a successful AI system actually look
like? Okay. So now that we understand why it caused water
AI is difficult, the next question becomes,
what does AI system actually look
like? Okay. Now that we understand the
complexity of the cost of the AI, let's talk about the
architectures. Okay. One of the biggest
mistakes I see is that people confuse a model with a
system. When someone says they are building
AI solutions, they often mean that they have the selected
model. GBT, Gemini, Core, but a model is
only one component. A successful AI
solution is required much more than that.
And that distinction is incredibly important. Okay. Today,
we have access to many powerful AI
products. To think a model is easier than ever. The
difficult part is designing everything around it,
where does the knowledge come from? How does the workflow
operate? Who is responsible for
decisions? How is quality monitor? How is trust maintained?
These questions determine whether a
project succeeds, not a model which marks.
Okay. Let's look at simplified architectures.
Notice something different. The model sits in the middle,
not on the top. Not the problem,
but in the middle. Yeah. So this is the five pages that I
showed earlier. So normally, we have to
consider about the users. Without the users, nothing else
matters. Users do not care about
what model you use. But users never compare the benchmark
scores, but they care about the outcome.
Can it solve my problem? Can I test it? Does it make my
work easier? Not the technologies.
They care about the outcome. So
you have to consider about this.
And the application, the next layer is applications. This
is where AI meet the workflow. Imagine that
an employee receives a recommendation from AI. If using
that recommendation requires switching
system, copying data, performing, so complicated. Yeah. The
best AI system will fit naturally into
the existing workflow. And now this is the AI layer. That
off-do are familiar with that.
The LAA provider reasoning, IG provides the knowledge
access, the agents coordinate the
actions, the tools interact with external system. The
broader AI system are becoming ecosystem
rather than the standalone models. Okay. And then this is
another layer. The knowledge is one of the
most underrated components of the AI
system without the knowledge. The knowledge is
outdated or incorrect. The performance will suffer. And the
enterprise system, this is one
of the key thing as well. This is where the AI start
generating the measurable values.
The real organizations operate through the system, the CRM
system, ERP system, customer service,
the government database, healthcare financial system. If AI
cannot connect in to operational
system, it remains an isolated intelligence layers. It
doesn't create the values. Okay.
And then the last one is the JAKA finance. Yeah. This is
one of the key component that makes the
people trust as well. When we talk about this, we talk
about the security, the compliance,
the how to monitor it, audited, risk management. Yeah.
Without the governance, organizations cannot
trust AI. And without trust, the organizations cannot scale
the AI. Yeah. This layer becomes
increasingly important. So this is what I just mentioned
earlier. So I would like to address here
again that AI border is just only the iceberg tip. But we
have a lot of things that we have
to consider about. So many teams just celebrate when the
prototype works. And of course, yeah,
they are really happy. But the prototype is not the
destination. The prototype demonstrates
possibilities. And a prototype demonstrates the
disabilities. A platform demonstrates
the how can you scale. The impact itself
will demonstrate the values. So it each stage
requires different skills, different stakeholders,
different investment, and different ways of
thinking. So let's step back a bit. Yeah. Yeah. We now we
understand about the AI system. So what
problem should we actually solve? Yeah. Because the
technology only matters when it improves the
human life. And that is where the impact begins. This is
the examples of other domains that
that normally have the big impact. Yeah. Okay. So many
hackathon teams begin with the technologies.
Begin with the technologies, a model, a framework, a tool.
But I would like, I would encourage you to
begin somewhere else. Start with the meaningful problems.
After spending time discussing the
architecture system and something else. Yeah. Technology is
a tool. The real goal of the project
is to improve life of the people. The real goal is creating
meaningful impact. Whether you evaluate
an AI project, ask simple questions. If this succeeds,
whose life becomes better? If you cannot
answer that query, you may not be solving the right
problem. Technology matters, but the people
matter most. So you have to create on solving the problem
of the people. Okay. Not every problem
deserves an AI solution. Some problems are interesting, but
unimportant. Some problems are
important, but impossible to solve. So
when we evaluate opportunities, I like to use
four criteria. The first one is, is the problem important?
Can it be scaled? Yeah. Can it be
scaled? Can it be used more than one or two or 10 or
million people? Is it feasible? Yeah. It means
it is possible to make the money, for example. This is
measurable. The Stormcaps AI project
usually performs well across four dimensions. So the great
project normally starts with the
great problems. So this is just for example, we can
consider about doing the project with
digital thread. This is because they also face many
language barriers, regulatory barriers,
the market intelligence challenges, customer support
challenges, and many things that when you
do the threading across borders, there are many areas that
you can address. AI can reduce the
barriers to international thread. This is one of the key.
Another area is about the public services.
Public services also affect
millions of people every day also. So many
citizens struggle to access information. Government
services are often fragmented
and also the migration and process. So imagine that the AI
assistant can help the citizens
understand the government services
in their own language, for example.
And health care is one of the most promising areas for AI
as well. AI can make the health care
knowledge more accessible. This is another area also that
has a big impact because many people
are involved. The education is fundamental about access to
the knowledge. For example, AI tutoring,
multi-lingual language learning,
accessibility from remote areas, or personalized
education. Education becomes scalable when knowledge
becomes accessible. Using AI will
help a lot. So this is the thing that many people focus on
this problem about climate change.
Climate change reduces AI to use the better information and
the faster decision to analyze
the large volume of data, predict the risk, improve the
disaster response, support the
residents planning. Yeah, so this is what AI helps. This
slide summarizes the entire journey we have
discussed. So normally everything starts with the problems
and then they come to the data,
then the workflow, then the AI, and finally the impact.
Notice where AI appears, right? It
doesn't appear at the beginning, but it appears near the
end because we focus on the successful
team. Normally start with the problem
first. Technology will amplify the solutions.
Okay, let me end this section just before I go to the next
one with a slightly provocative statement.
Yeah, the world doesn't need another AI demo. But what we
need is we need the solutions that can
help improve the pain point, improve the healthcare,
improve the education, public services,
climate. So what we need is we need more
solutions. So this is probably the last one
that I would like to spend my time talking about this
before I go to the Q&A. Yeah, at this point
we have identified the problem with solving. Yeah, but that
is another important question. Even if we
can build something, should we, for example, less
responsible AI is not about the compliance.
When people hear the phrase less responsible AI, many
immediate think about regulations, compliance,
policies, legal requirements. And when those things matter,
they are not where responsible AI begins.
Responsible AI begins with trust. Yeah, this is a very
important concept because no matter how
powerful your AI model or AI system is, if the people do
not have it, they will not use it.
And if they do not use it, it cannot create
the impact. The trust is the foundation of
adoptions and adoption is the foundation
of impact. Yeah, throughout the history,
technology has continuously expanded what humans are
capable of doing. AI also is no different.
Today, we can automate the decisions, we can generate the
content, we can analyze the massive
amount of information, we can predict the outcome, but
capabilities alone does not justify the
department because we can build something that does not
necessarily mean we should, as AI becomes
more powerful, acting the right patience becomes more
important than building the right model.
And so, yeah, imagine we deploy an AI system. This is, for
example, that capable of identifying
potential criminals using the public surveillance camera,
the system is highly accurate,
perhaps 95% accurate. Would you
deploy it? Yeah, we have the technologies.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, this is for example. Some people will
immediately say, yes, we should do it.
Others will immediately say no. Yeah, this agreement is
exactly why responsible AI matters.
Yeah, the first question is not the
technical. The first question is societal
technology creates the capabilities, the society decides
how that capability should be used.
Yeah, yeah, this is for example, yeah, you don't need to do
the pope. But yeah, this is what I just
mentioned. This has been discussed widely in many countries
also. If AI system can identify
with a potential criminal from the surveillance cameras
with a 95% accuracy, should the government
deploy it? Many people say, oh, no, no, no, I do not want
you to detect my face. Yeah, and then
someone may steal that data for something else. So this is
a kind of the controversial topic also.
Yeah, so yeah, this is the thing that I would like to
address again. The benefits, the
responsible AI, yeah, yeah, yeah, we have to consider about
who benefit from our AI system,
but make sure that no one that makes sure that you have to
consider about the impact or the harmful
to some audiences as well. So, but at the end, you have to
identify who gains them, the values,
and also who could be harmed. Yeah,
yeah, you have to consider about not to
do the system that had the bias, the exclusions, or provide
the misinformation, the privacy,
or do not have the safety, because every
technology creates both value and risk.
Okay, this is the last tool that I would like to talk
about, the AI failure case studies.
Beauty AI is easy, you know, but predicting human behavior
is very hard. Okay, this is the first
example that I, the first example is Microsoft. Hey, yeah,
sorry to talk about the brand, but this is
the case study everywhere. In the year 2016, Microsoft
launched an AI chatbot on the Twitter.
The goal was simple. Yeah, Tei was designed to learn from
conversations with the users.
Unfortunately, users quickly discover how
to manipulate the system. Within hours, Tei
began generating offensive and inappropriate content. Yeah,
Microsoft had to shut the system
down in less than 24 hours. The technology was the model
learn, but the problem is it learned
from the wrong behaviors. And this is the last slide before
I jump into the Q&A sessions.
The second example comes from Amazon.
Amazon experienced with an AI system to help
either the job applicants. The system was
trained using the historical handling data.
At first, it seems reasonable, but there was a hidden
problem. Historical hiring decisions
contain historical biases. As a result,
the AI learned pattern that favor male
applicants over the female applicants. The system was not
intentionally biased. It simply learned
from the biased historical data. Eventually, Amazon left
this project behind. So this is
of my presentation. At the end, I would like to address
that. Do not focus on the AI model.
Focus on the problem. The people consider other factors not
related to the technology. If you
would like to scale your project bigger. Let me pass my
session back to Professor Rota Poop.
Thank you for your challenge. Very interesting. Actually, I
am a researcher. Sometimes we
talk about the prototype and the commercialization. We need
to scale up. The scale up is definitely
not easy. Thank you for guiding
and the direction for the hackathon
tonight. We have two questions
in the chat box. The first one,
is how do you handle language and context that are
only represented in training
data? Let me see the questions.
Yes. How do you handle language and context that are
under represented in the training data?
In the training data, right? I think that
the language is one of the challenges also. At the moment,
I think comparing with the past few
months, the language model, the language
model of the out of the box AI, much better.
So far, I think this type of language is less and less.
Yes. Luckily, what I have to do is I think we need to be
more careful about the culture and
the style of the language for each
country. For example, I give you an example.
We build the project of the AI for Chinese
languages. But the style of the how to use
Chinese in China is different. It's
not the same as how they use in Singapore
or somewhere else. Even the Chinese language that we use
for our customers in Taiwan and the
customers in China, of course, the writing
is not the same. Because in Taiwan, they use
traditional Chinese. But in mainland China, they use
simplified Chinese. What we have to train
the model is we have to make sure that the model or the
data that we use to train is specific
to the people that we are targeting with. For example, just
even the English language also.
We have to consider about the data,
about the culture that we use to train the AI
to match with our target audiences.
I think this is help. This is help.
Okay. And for the second question.
Second question, you mentioned about the trust in the
keyword. The second question is about
the trust that you mentioned. How would
you build the trust in AI outputs that use
Sowai skeptics or black box
recommendations? That is really challenging also. Because
that's why we need to comply. One of the things that when
we do the project is we need to
understand about the law and regulations of that country.
For example, when we do the project in Thailand or we do
the project in China or we do the project
in Singapore. Because I think the users, when they trust,
they trust the government more than us.
Yeah, for sure. What we need to do
is we need to make sure that to try
everywhere that we comply with the
compliance, the laws or the standards that the
industry or the government
enforce. That's why we need sometimes
our customers need to comply to get the certificate or they
have to show about the audit report
to ensure that their customers trust
that they comply with what their government
enforce. Yeah. Okay, okay. Actually, we have more than one
question. But because the time is
in, but I think I will send you another
question by email and you can answer. Let's
point back to me again. Tonight, thank you so much for
sharing everything tonight. And could
everyone give a big applause or a big hug to Dr. Vlaanju
again? Okay. Yeah, thank you. Thank you.
Okay. Hi.
Mr. Xiong Zhang. Yes. Yeah. Can I call
you Mr. Zhang? Yeah, sure. Oh, can I start
share? Okay. Okay. Welcome to the hackathon webinar. Okay.
Okay. It is now the last of the
speaker tonight. My absolute pleasure to
introduce the last speaker, Mr. Xiong Zhang.
Mr. Xiong Zhang is the executive
director and chief AI officer of the AI 2030.
A global initiative dedicated to mainstreaming responsible
AI to benefit humanity. A recognized
leader in applying emerging technologies for social impact.
He has over two decades of the
experience at the intersection of AI, FinTech, blockchain
and sustainability. Today, he will be
presenting on a topic responsible AI for digital trade.
Please join me in giving a warm welcome to
Mr. Xiong Zhang. Okay. Mr. Xiong Zhang,
the floor is yours. Thank you very much. And
I really appreciate the opportunity to be able to meet
everyone and also have discussion on
leveraging AI for global trade. And before I start my
presentation, I really like the question
raised for the last panel and maybe I can just quickly just
go over a few of them. And the first
point about the underrepresentation, and we developed a
framework around that. And number
one is that we have to recognize that the problem exists.
And number two is that a lot of models are
built in the closed labs, frontier labs. And then a lot of
those questions actually cannot be
addressed by others if the frontier labs
don't really just incorporate the principle
to bring the underrepresentation data and context into
that. And we all know that now many of the
data are just not in model, AI model training from the
frontier models. And that itself is not
addressed. And I think to just having the global pressure
and to request the frontier lab to
adopt the principles to just address that is very
important. Of course, that they also recognize the
problem and we see in many of those reports. But then
another direction to that is also not only
through the pressure to the frontier lab, also just looking
to the open AI models. There that's
many times that global cells can put a lot of emphasis or
input into the open models where
there that's the bottom up approach can potentially add a
great value to make those models
to be more representative and address the context related
issues by leveraging the expertise in those
areas which are less represented or the population or
community are less represented. And how would
you build trust in AI output and there that's AI excellency
itself is very important where that's
in many companies, especially in the regulated industry and
to make AI explainable itself
is becoming a very important piece of their work.
Otherwise, many times that's in the US where that
I'm based that's in the financial industry or in other
regulated industry. If you cannot explain
your output and then your regulators will not be happy
about it and then you may get fine.
And so there that's just there are tons of tools to make AI
explainable and which just link
the output with the input and then you need to be able to
trace back. And that is of again,
there's tons of publication use cases and happy to share.
And so also would be correct to state
that's for responsible AI to be a reality there would need
to be some universally adopted best
practices. That is a yes and no question because I think
anything if we claim universally
adopted best practice that itself the statement itself is
undermining the uniqueness of a lot of
communities or population or context. So something worked
for somewhere for some population for some
company might not work in other places, but that doesn't
make it less available to have global
best practice as a reference. And which is where that's at
least a lot of those best practice
provide those question lists where that's
if you work on something and then have you
address those questions and those can help you to adopt. We
developed this toward a global
responsible AI framework as a study and
we analyzed over 100 some responsible way
principles standards from the international organization,
specific individual countries
and industries and frontier labs. And at
the beginning that we want to just see that's
whether we are able to even to come up with
responsible AI framework, which is globally
adaptable. But our conclusion there is a question mark. And
because many times when you just
review the standards and all that you will see that
something which is as cool in this
scenario for this population may be seen
as not as a cold dark in the other context,
similar thing. But there are some foundations which really
can just be more plausible across
the different contexts. So then it's a yes and no question
answer. So that just quickly go. I was
inspired by the earlier speaker and the question I want to
just quickly jump there. So now that's
let me just quickly go to my part and where that's for my
presentation is AI for global trade.
And I think this hack for myself is very, very timely
because in general when you just look at
where AI can potentially contribute, a global trade is an
area where that's AI can do a lot.
And when we talk about especially the global south or the
international development where that
AI can just really address some of the problems which have
been existing for a long time
and from the cost saving because we all know in the global
supply chain and many times that's
the supply chain management occur a lot of costs and those
costs can be reduced by leveraging AI
and then that benefit can be translated into the supply
chain, the factories and all that.
And then that directly can result into the betterment or
the profits in the trading part.
The second part is we all know about the trade finance
where that's many of the manufacturers
or trading partners really rely heavily on the credits and
other financial instruments provided
within the supply chain but many times that's the supply
chain finance itself has a lot of
inefficiency and the blockchain that sorry AI can
definitely help to address that. But a lot of
those benefits which are related to the developing
countries can only be realized and if
the developing countries are in the room
and here that's just to show you a few data.
Although trade can just leave over 30% potential leave to
war trade by 2040 and there that's
when we look at the income gain for low and mid income and
then there's a very clear current gap
then when you look at the currently the
notable AI models are being used or developed
in 87% of them are in the home of the high
income countries and then they only have 70%
of the world population. So those disparity just shared
this is very urgent and we as AI 2030
have our name because we want to communicate this urgency
where there are things that need to be done
can be done the window to change occur from we have a
couple years where that we can really just
to all working together to make that change. I think this
global hackathon is one of those
great efforts where that identifying the problem bring the
innovators together and then to really
bring the real benefits to the global trade and that's the
benefit of the community. So when we
talk about how AI can really just contributing to global
trade and there are many many different
areas where there is inefficiency where there is high cost
where there is data is very available
and also decisions are repeatable and naturally where AI
could really play a very important role
and a good example from the trade finance and where that's
by leveraging AI and if you combine
AI also even with blockchain where that's the way in the
trade finance you can create the
different type of credit score and the credit related risk
can be analyzed automatically by AI
and then that can just really reducing to make a lot of
entities are not credit worthy or just
the shipping related documents or shipping
trade documents can immediately play a very
important role to provide finance for a lot of the
stakeholders. So definitely here we have
a lot of numbers I don't have time to dive deep on it but
you can just look into that while I'm
talking and the second part is the custom
and documentation and my first job was doing
international trade and I remember where that's no matter
it's just from the shipping document,
the place of a region and the tons of documents which
literally when I was starting my career
and I feel that my work is so boring and also it was so
tedious not productive because I finished
bachelor degree and I feel I have a lot to offer but a lot
of my time is really just dealing with
documents go to different departments getting all the
documents here and there but each time
it's really just one human to another human and then to
just pass exactly the same information
but if AI are used in the custom and
documentation process where that process
can just really take a lot of human related work out of
that and then that itself can also just
increase efficiency dramatically and of course supply chain
visibility is another very important
piece of that where if you are in the global supply chain
you know that's the data of shipment
or in the contract no matter you use FOB or CIF and where
that's those days and all that are very
important to know where the goods are and whether you are
able to deliver on time, whether you are
able to just the goods can arrive on time and those are
very very important and many times those
trade conflicts arise where that's you
know visibility doesn't exist where that AI
have already just brought a lot of visibility not potential
have brought a lot of visibility into
that because AI's ability to just processing large quantity
of data and at a timely manner
and a lot of those efficiency are just you know human
related inefficiency you know
cause a lot of visibility really issue artists you know
much less you know if we just bring AI
into the process and then there's non-tariff measures and
illicit trade and laundering and
we all know that you know there are a lot of sanctions and
you know for many many you know
the reason why the place of origin is important is because
of you know there are a lot of
you know sanctions or international trade policies which
you know need to just impact each of the
trading you know transaction and if again bring you know
human into the process and you see
inefficiency and where that's you know if AI can help to
just processing documents and then
at a timely manner and then where that's a lot of those
potential you know inefficiency can be you
know taken away from the process and then really just speed
up the the the trading and the
transaction process and also gets you know a lot of returns
and also you know potential you know
trade related tariff reduction all that
back to you know the trading partners and
when I talk about all that you know those are not something
which just in theory we have seen
a lot of you know very concrete large
scale adoption which you know have occurred in
you know here I I list the majority of the the use cases or
examples are from developing countries
and from the air you know customs risk targeting and you
see the Brazil and then you know from
the SME alternative data credit you see you know and my
bank so yeah these are some of the areas
where you already see solutions because you know this is
the hackathon I will not dive deep into
each of those you know areas or case studies but my message
here is that you know leveraging AI to
to just really create benefit for global trade itself you
know it's not early stage it is you
know has already at scale if you are building some
solutions and you know from scratch you
need to understand the the scope and also understand the
landscape and at AI 2030 we also run
you know incubator accelerator program every year I you
know review at least a thousand of startup
um applications and also you know the pitch decks and a lot
of time that's one of the key
problem I see is that you know the innovators have not done
sufficient research regarding
the competitors or you know all the landscape then you know
they claim that's you know nobody's
doing this or there is a market position that we are the
leader and a lot of those claim on
just factually not true and I think you know to just now we
have AI and it's very easy for us
to do a much better uh risk background research and make
sure that's you know whatever um solution
you are trying to build and you know the landscape well you
know what are the solution which already
you know are scaled by which country who
can potentially be your partner your customer
and who are your competitor and where they are in their
process and all you know these are some of
the use cases so which are they you know at a scale and are
you you know do you want to just
reinvent or contributing to those those scalable you know
use cases or you want to identify
something new so those are some of the you know question or
comments I want to just get to you
know the participants of the hackathon and you know here
again this is just some of the
you know name dropping because I think it's very important
to know that you know when you are you
know doing hackathon and one thing you know in the past we
did was we invited the global company
to do reverse pitch reverse pitch for our startups meaning
that's many times that startups the
solution are you know at the early stage and then the
corporate enterprise process is very tedious
and you know it's not easy for startup to navigate the work
problems that you know the enterprise
have and how to just you know navigate their internal
process for procurement or PLC pilot
building and but I think you know to just know that which
company are piloting you know what
and I think at least this gave you you know an idea and
there are potential opportunities
if not from them at least from their competitors meaning
that's you know if they as the key players
have done something in for example you know credit risk or
from the shaping documentation you know
or from the trade finance and then you understand you know
potentially another larger enterprise
of one in the same you know sector working on the same type
of use case potentially have that
demand where that you can you know easily to just you know
identify the top 10 or top five
where that's you you can just you know look into and then
we who are supporting you in that process
can also just based on your research try to open door for
you and see that you know if you know
you don't want to go to UPS because they already have have
something maybe you know we go to you
know FedEx or we go to Maskey and different organization
and if you don't want to go to Alibaba
and then you know there are other e-commerce you know
platform Amazon others you know so
there that's by knowing that who have deployed the AI for
you know the global trade related use cases
that can give you some idea number one to
understand what have been done you you know
either try to just do it differently or try to avoid that
use case or if you really try to do
something similar you also know that's who you can pitch
when you really have a you know solid
solution my next one is you know it's really and this is
more from the ecosystem players no matter
you are universities or UN organization or you know the
government officials where that's you
know although you know every one of us know and talk about
the AI related benefits but you know
AI can also compound you know a lot of create a lot of new
risks for the developing countries
and I just believe in some and I want to make sure that
when we talk about AI we are not
just talking blindly to embrace AI say hey this is
something universally good and they are
university best practice which just you know everyone
should just adopt should so there are
very clear new risks that so everyone need to be aware of
and you know if you are a government
official UN or you know ecosystem player there are things
you know this group can you know need
to to be doing or at least create space for you know the
broader ecosystem to to discuss contribute
and then find a solution and number one is that in many you
know when we talk about AI and then
now a lot of AI is the leave you know is living in the
software and that being in the computer
and leaving the internet and where that's you know if the
the you know there are countries
our community are not connected and naturally that they
just you know when you talk about all
the benefits they just cannot enjoy any of those benefits
because you know there are the basic you
know connectivity problem is has not been addressed and you
know second is you know around the data
center related imbalance as you know you can see us china
hold half of the world data centers and
you know there that's so and and also there's access to
cloud uh uh clouds and and all that
so then there's the infrastructure related you know
imbalance and then you know how both from
at the you know UN level or at the country level that's you
know how you can just create either
alternative solution or you know bring AI to the edge
devices or you know you need all from
distributed computing or just you know have your own data
center and or just uh have partnership
with the global you know data center you know the the
bigger player and every organ you know country
may need to have your very clear AI infrastructure related
you know strategy and all that that is a
priority you know in the long run if AI benefits you are
you are looking into you know how to
leverage AI to just advance the economy and of course you
know when we you know earlier we are
already from the question uh we have folks talked about it
and you know about the bias about
anti-representation about you know the exability
transparency and a lot of you know
AI related risk which are you know really
important because you know without AI and then
individual have bias individual you know a company have
transparency related issues however all those
are just you know at a you know anecdotal level where
individual bias may just you know be
translated the impact will be translating to one person or
your direct customers but AI can really
you know scale bias scale you know those you know better
impact at a global scale and impact
everyone so if that is not being addressed and then you're
introducing your AI and having inherit
all the bias and then that can just you know really you
know create a negative impact for you know
many people good example is you you know if you are a
global shaping company and then you use the
AI and then your AI is just for example and are not you
know have significant bias issue towards
for example developing country you know situation and that
is of you know when you're introducing
such an AI you know before if you know people or humans are
in the process then they can just
recognize that and if anything happens they
can immediately just you know to intervene
but the AI you know is always is you
know have to have enough data and enough
incidents happen then that you know signal or pattern will
be just understood by AI that's
you know many are the impact by that time there's a job
displacement cyber exposure you know energy
I want to emphasize a little bit more here that's you know
it's very clear that's you know AI related
and no matter from the data center or from the you know
leveraging AI now to do basic search
or just the changing of human behavior rely on AI each one
of you know those activity just creates
a lot more you know carbon emission and water consumption
and then we are entered into a phase
where that's you know AI is competing with basic human
needs so then that's you know the ones who
impact the most will be in the developing country and I
think from the policy maker and you know the
organizations need to really be aware of that and make sure
that's you know there's a you know when
AI competes you know with basic human
needs and then there are need to be measures or
guardrails around that to make sure that you know humans
are being protected in the AI economy
and they thought you know what can be done within you know
some this time framework and where that's
you know there are at least some of the international
efforts around this but again that's
you know I highly appreciate UNSCAP is leading you know way
in Asia-Pacific and then to just bring
a lot of important stakeholders together identifying you
know from the standards to the
you know innovation and then to the policy dialogue I think
those efforts are really important
and the five priority for you know trade
negotiators this probably you think this
might not be very relevant for this audience and I will not
you know focus on that. My last slide
is really about you know AI 2030 who we are and why you
know I'm here sharing this with you
so AI 2030 is a non-profit our main goal is to mainstream
responsible research development use
of AI by 2030 we have over 6 000 members across 60
countries and we focus on responsible AI,
AI for good and AI for all and the priority for us include
advanced human leveraging AI to
advance human potential and promote scalable open AI
infrastructure and leveraging AI to solve
planetary problem and challenge and that's why you know all
the issues that we discuss and we really
care about and then we can act at least to just claim we
know there are 6 000 people in this 60
countries who share the same vision share
the same goal and want to just the mainstream
responsible AI by 2030 we hope that you are also just join
this movement and help us to just really
you know make the AI benefit humanity and that's pretty
much you know what I want to share so thank
you very much. Okay thank you for sharing Mr. Chang so we
have one question from the shared box
what would you make the difference between an AI tool that
gets adopted by the government
versus one that stays a prototype?
Yeah this is not only by government in general when you
just look at any you know AI related
application and you see a few processes
there and number one there is you know design
there's a planning there's a design there's
a build there's a POC pilot there's you know
last skill adoption so that can be you know true for
government that can be true for enterprise
and where that's you know when you just look at you know at
a different stage where that's or
if you are a different entity and your focus are different
meaning that if you are a startup
startup and your focus is really you know looking at how
who are whose problem I try to solve and
is that the problem is scalable and how do I go to market
and who can help me to go to market with
and you know how do I just you know if so those are the
questions for a startup you know you
you need to care about then from the you know the
enterprise a lot of time is internal POC pilot
and many of the POC pilots are just you know ready for
learning purpose so if you are a startup
and then you you want to you know get involved in the you
know learning process for enterprise
you also don't it really depends you know where you are if
you know you your expectations the
enterprise will adopt your solution from pilots and also
help you to scale and then if they only
want to learn they have no you know the desire to do that
and then that you know you may you know
have a lot of investment into that that doesn't give you
any financial return so you need to be
very clear and how you interact you know with your
enterprise to get a demand right when you
talk about the government related AI adoption and the
government have two different roles one role
is you know government are the adopter of AI then there are
you know how to leveraging AI to deliver
public service and that is how for you know you can treat
the government as really you know any
other enterprise where that's then they have their internal
process but you know government can also
just play a very different role and which is to create the
infrastructure and also to you know
support a certain you know functionalities you know that is
how if a government introducing
that to practice and you know those becoming the
infrastructure for your AI tools or for your and
then you need to definitely you know a lot of government
provide for example data data sets
for you to you know do a lot of you know from the open
government then they just create a lot of you
know open data where that you can use the open data to you
know build your tools then they also
you know introducing for example some of the computing
resources and then to all open source
you know platform so all those are benefits where you know
your startup can can benefit from yeah
okay thank you for for answer okay now
so we have the AI developer community here
what do you think about the AI
standardization for the role of AI developer?
Sorry?
The AI standardization should be we
should have the standard to control or to
for the AI developer to to comply
them to to save as every country.
Yeah so this is very fragmented and where that's we just
you know in the past few years
we contributed to the UN Global Digital Compact you know
input we provide feedback to the US
National AI Action Plan we provided you
know input to Singapore's AI governance
public consultation and many you know so when we provide
the input into into you know different
different process and there are you know a number of things
we identify number one is that you know
for certain countries there are you know
and certain areas there are some commonalities
and it's very easy for you know countries even you have
different standards and all that the
standard looks very similar so in for those you know areas
the challenge to individual company
to comply is minimal because you know they are very similar
standard they just one you know
there's a consensus or they just copy each other and but
there are areas which are you know
fundamentally different and for example you know whether AI
can be used for you know autonomous
weapons or AI you know the how to leverage AI for defense
and or you know there's you know in
the regulated industry that there are a lot of very
concrete you know country specific regulations
and which can create barriers for others to just and I
think for those you know there are three
levels things that need to be happen number one is you know
from researchers need to just you know
dive deep into those identifying you know if again go back
to trade global trade and what kind of
you know AI policy or standards which are not standardized
enough which create the biggest
barrier highest stake and then you know how that can be
addressed that itself will be a very
important research topic need a lot of you know capability
enter into that second part is that
you know as you know UN I think play a very important role
by convening you know different
countries and not working on a global standard for
everything but identifying those you know
high risk high stake area very you know single single
policy or single standards for single use
case and where that's you know to just really have you know
anything if you want to be make it
comprehensive it'll be difficult but if it's really one
issue and then there is a higher
possibility to just achieve you know the the expected goal
and the last one is that you know
the standard setting bodies you know need really just you
know to working together so how to just
make different standards interoperable and that is how we
did a research called you know G20 AI
Regulation Index we looked at you know G20 you know
countries AI you know regulations and we
scored them and then from the highest to the lowest the
difference in the lowest is 0.3
and the highest like 70 and you can within the G20
countries and as you can see you know there are
a lot of difference you just you know players the ecosystem
players that just need to bear because
you know we have to recognize the reality and AI standard
AI regulation is very fragmented and
then a lot of work can be done need to be done okay thank
you okay Dr. Wollong-yoo are you here
uh yes yes yes yes okay okay we have the the question that
would like both of you to sharing
or discuss the question is about the if
AI generated advice turns out to be wrong
who bears the reliability you first uh Dr. Wollong-yoo uh
yeah yeah of course uh the the the
builder yeah yeah uh yeah because yeah i'm not sure about
about the if if it actually yeah i
just saw the questions if the yes yes okay the advice uh
turned out to be wrong uh definitely
uh yeah it itself yeah cannot bear the
the responsibility yeah yeah but but the
but the response responsibility yeah always remain uh yeah
with the human and organizations who build
it yeah i can generate the recommendations
uh uh yeah i can generate the content but but
AI itself they cannot bear the responsibility so the
accountability always belong to the
organizations or the decision the design maker who does the
AI question how about your opinion
okay yeah this question seemed to be easy but it's very
difficult and you know number one is that
what kind of advice and you know in in some of jurisdiction
that they define you know the for
they they cost significant use cases where that's you know
for more significant use cases and AI's
liability is very different for non-significant use cases
so if you know there's for example
driver's vehicles or is the financial advice that people
lost money or people lost life or health
care really and then those advices and naturally that's uh
you know then there's a very clear
legal base in some of the jurisdictions how that's uh you
know um liability is being translated into
and so there's also you know to to make those liability you
know to have the foundation in the
legal system and the many jurisdiction also enter into the
new law making process so that is you know
one part of the complication the second part of
complication is that you know many of the AI
um application are built you know on the foundational
models and where that's they don't
have control on the foundational models and if you know
that's a liability you know that's advice
and the mistake coming from the foundation
model which they just don't have any control
and whose responsibility is that that is self you know i
agree with you know that's definitely
definitely shouldn't be the user and there should be you
know but you know within the builder because
the AI building process you know without AI and a lot of
time you see you know one company own that
product but now that with the foundation models and all
that's that product coming from an
organization potentially that organization don't own the
whole piece of that product and so then
you need to dive very deep into the procurement contract
between you know the foundation model
and the you know the developer or the company who own that
product and then if you know that's a
procurement contract to protect this you know the product
owner and naturally you know then
they will bear you know the but if that procurement
contract don't protect them and then they have to
you know really own the whole liability where that's you
know part of them they just have no
control so that's why procurement AI procurement as a skill
set becoming very important the last
part is that's you know who bears and then is again you go
to your last question which jurisdiction
you're talking about in many of the jurisdiction there's
just no loss and so you know if there's
no law and you can try to there's a wrong you know advice
and then a lot of time if the law
doesn't protect your rights and then you are the only one
who will bear that you know consequence
but the advice to the you know builders or the companies
are that's you know even there's no law
but you don't want to lose your customer trust so if you
know you can win a legal case but you cannot
win your customer's heart so if you just build with intent
that's hey they are not protected
I'm going to just you know do it in the wrong way when you
lost your your the trust from your
customer even you know you don't have legal consequences
and then your your company will
just you know will not be beneficial from those you know
misbehavior or misconduct yeah
okay okay we still have enough time for the any audience
want to share in or ask some question
light your hand up
yeah I see a question to me we have a solution already for
a trusty digital trade how can we
present it to you and you just reach out
to me on LinkedIn and happy to look at it
I see I see okay no okay okay I think uh
this late night in Bangkok how about your time
Mr. Zhang uh it's 8 49 a.m nine time okay okay just morning
okay okay okay okay today uh I would
like to uh say thank you for all of you for sharing and I
would like to uh the the floor
give a big applause uh to both of you again and uh in the
name of the host of the hackathon
I would like to see you again in the final round maybe for
uh give some comments like commentator
something like that okay
okay thank you thank you thank you
very much thank you thank you okay bye bye
bye