So, yeah, good evening everybody. Welcome to the last
session of our workshop series. We
have been together since 1st of June.
I'm sorry Nikita, I cannot hear you.
I cannot hear too.
Nikita, you have some problem?
Nikita, we lost you.
Hologly, we don't hear you.
We still cannot hear you.
No.
I hope my voice is coming through now.
Yes, now I can hear.
Okay, I'm so sorry for the technical problems, but I was
just saying that welcome everybody.
Today is the last session of our workshop and we have been
together since 1st June and today we will finish this
workshop series together as well.
Today in this Q&A session, we will answer all the questions
that you have sent us so far and we will try to get through
all of them in the time that we have today.
We have Dr. Vittada, Ajahn Ratapoom and Ajahn Tanavit to
answer all the questions you have today.
So, hopefully we can make this session good.
So, all the questions that we have received so far can be
categorized into different categories. So, let's start with
the research process and evaluation related questions.
And I think these questions are meant for Juntong. So, let
me start with the first question, which is, the last time
you collected data for the specific economic pillar, what
was your process from start to finish?
Please go ahead.
Okay, I think I've been taking the past two sessions and
introduced the human lawyers process.
And I've also received the summation of assignments. So,
basically, if you remember what I mentioned, first you need
to identify your research question.
And then you need to find the request sources, basically
like the government website and the official legal
documents and the primary source and the
secondary sources, the distinguished patronum.
And then you go to the legal text reading part. Basically,
you just read the legal text and read the law document. You
find the document and then you need to read the document.
And also try to analyze why this specific section or
article is related with the indicator you were collecting
data. And also, apart from the citation and also you give
the interpretation of this legal text.
And in the end, all those information, you need to insert
into our database, which has a format requirement, which
are already sent to you or all of you, all the teams when I
was asking about the assignments.
So, if you still have this question, even though after you
already done the assignments, you still have this question,
please refer to my previous
presentations and also the recording.
We have already provided all of them in the knowledge
portal. And after that, if you still have this kind of
question, then you can just email us.
Yeah, one of the follow up questions to this is when
searching for legal text, are there any specific databases,
websites or tools that you typically consult and do you
have a specific order in which you
use these tools, databases and websites?
I am not sure, like I totally got this question. So I think
like this, like, does this mean the research, like you
research the legal document among nowhere?
Or like you refer to the to searching the legal text in the
legal document, which means that they're the two steps. The
first one is to research the legal
document, which is the basically the process.
We have already talked and I already answered in the first
question. And so if you are asking about the searching the
legal text in the legal document, which means like you
already got the law and you're reading the legal text.
And I remember in the second session, our law professor has
already told us how to read the legal text. So if you have
this kind of question, you can refer to
other materials in the second session.
When it comes to law documents as well, we know that across
different countries, we're looking at different local
languages and domestic languages, etc. So how do you
process, what do you prefer usually?
Do you usually prefer handling non-English documents or
English documents and how would you process scan PDFs or
legal texts that are only available in local languages?
So I understood this as two types of documents. So firstly,
you're talking about the scan PDF. And if the scan PDF is
in English or any other languages you are familiar with.
And then I think for human lawyers, that's not a problem.
It's a PDF and you can read the text anyway. It's not like
a totally blurry or something like that. You can read it
and then you go to the normal process
we've already introduced many times.
But if it refers to the native languages that you're not
familiar with, for some countries, they have multi-language
version. And in this case, we prioritize their native
language because the native language version is the most
updated one. Normally, it's the most updated one.
And the English version, they will also update that but not
very promptly update the English version. So in this case,
let's prioritize the non-English version, but take the
English version as a reference.
And for how to read the non-English version, I mean, for
human lawyers, I just go to the most traditional way. Just
use the translation application, for example, like Google
translation or depot translation. Use this kind of app.
And when the AI was not good enough, we only use this
translation app. But the text is very robotic. So you can
read it and it's very robotic. But the meanings are often
good. I'm not saying that
absolutely good from the translation app.
But then we have AI, but AI sometimes can upload this
non-English document or you can copy the non-English
paragraph to AI and ask it to help you translate or
interpret. But I have to say it's not 100% accurate.
Sometimes AI just make up things and give you the
inaccurate ones. And so in this case, I would suggest that
you use the translation application, like Google
translation or depot translation, together with the AI. So
basically, you got two versions of the results.
And then you cross-check them. And that's the best way I
can think. I mean, for human lawyers.
Yeah. In terms of translation, I think at this stage, if we
are making an automated tool, it's best to record the
non-English version and the English version as well.
Because when we make a legal and monetary database or we
put it out for lawyers to see, if lawyers from that country
are able to see our database and read the relevant
provision that we have picked out, it is valuable.
Right. So I agree that the latest law can be available
mostly in the domestic language, but it is good to record
like work documents, I guess.
Yes.
Yeah.
About government websites, actually, the next question
would be, are there any government websites that are
difficult to access or limited and automated searches? And
how do you handle those situations?
Well, I have to say, it happens. It happens because
sometimes we just cannot approach this government website.
It's because some national security consideration or any
other consideration. So it happens. So in this case, it
also depends on, is this just one specific government
website that was blocked or all the government websites?
All the government website was blocked. So if it's just one
government website, let's say the National Congress website
was blocked. Well, normally it's the National Legal
Database. And if it's blocked, you realize, let's say, you
realize you're looking for the Personal Data Protection
Act. And you cannot find this in
the Congress because it's blocked.
In the Congress website is blocked. And maybe it's time to
refer to the ministerial websites. For example, like the
Ministry of Trade, Ministry of Commerce. And in this case,
like the ministerial websites, they are also government
official websites. So in this case,
you may find the legal document there.
But if the government website just blocked, like totally
blocked, you cannot find the government official websites.
In this case, I would say, I mean, for us, there is no more
we can do. I would say like we refer to what we call the
second resources. And probably in this case, we need to
look into some legal review
from law firms or academic papers.
And sometimes they have the analysis of specific articles
or this kind of situation that this indicator refer to. But
since we call this the secondary source, we don't think
it's convincing enough because they're not official.
They're from the secondary interpretation.
So we'll still record this in our
database, but we will record in our note column.
Yeah, so I mean, that's the best way we can say. But I
mean, again, this is only, it just happened occasionally. I
would say like most of the time, you just have access to
the government legal website. And especially the first
batch country database. It's very organized. And I don't
think there's like government block thing.
Yeah, I think Singapore, Australia and Malaysia are pretty
well organized. So at least in the first round, this
problem shouldn't come. Yeah. But
maybe next round, for sure. Yeah.
Okay. And now that we have gone through the websites, we
have understood which legal text to sign and we have gone
through the legal text. Once you find an relevant legal
provision and you have identified it, what steps do you
take to enter it into the RDI database?
Well, I think it refers to the last step to insert the
information into the database. And for this, we have our
specific format requirements, because the database is not
just for us to read and we will publish into external
readers and which like we have our dashboard, we have our
database on our website. So everybody can see that, which
means we need to consistent the format.
And for that, I have in the in the fifth of June session, I
have already give you the assignment and with one of the
materials is the format requirements.
So if you want to know the details, I think you have to
refer to that document and this is the very detail the
format requirements to insert the database.
Okay.
Okay. Thank you so much, Junta. I'll get back to you
because my next question is for Koonvitada. We have a
question about some of our teams are very enthusiastic
about this project. So they are asking us, will coverage of
countries beyond the three round one economies like
Singapore, Australia and Malaysia be
considered in your final judgment scoring?
Or should teams focus exclusively on the countries that
have been designated to them during round one?
Thank you for the question and for Ntasia, soon for the
team. For round one, this is going to be submitted live by
20th July. We score additional
pillar of the three designated countries.
If you got to round one and go to the next round, then
additional countries will come into the matrix.
So for now, the country should focus on the three, the
participants in three countries and
then next round they can expand it to.
I am not going to stop you from adding countries, but we
will not just score them for now. We will keep them and
then look at your products with
additional country in the next round.
Okay.
If you get, if you pass through.
Yes. Okay. The next question and this is one of our one of
the interesting questions about the
indicator 7.5 in our RDTIF framework.
The question is that indicator 7.5 is a policy assessment
oriented framework. Will it be formally scored in the
hackathon? And if so, how is it
weighed in the evaluation rubric?
I believe the question was for indicator 6.5 because
indicator 7.5 is not a regulatory based indicator.
So, yeah.
Indicator 7.5 is not optional. It's mandatory. So it is
called as per usual standard mandatory indicators.
But for 6.5 we deliberately took it out from the data
template because the 6.5 is about being members of
agreements that have binding data flow.
So in that context, we are not advised you to include 6.5
which we intend to remove from
the competitions into the rubric.
Okay. So in that case 6.5 is still
something that we can keep out of scope.
Yeah. Okay. Perfect.
Okay. My next two questions will be for our colleagues from
KM University. So the first question for Ajahn Ratapoom or
Ajahn Thanavit, any one of you who wants to answer this,
it's about the evaluation methodology.
Will judges run the tool end to end or will the evaluation
primarily be based on the submitted
outputs, pitch deck and demonstration materials?
Yeah. I answered this question. I think that's the moment.
Okay. I think that will be primarily review the submit
output file and there may be the technical document, pitch
deck or your demonstration video.
And they may be also run the code, select part of the code
or request end to end demonstration to verify the
functionality and technical claim.
And then I think if you submit the LISA GitHub repository,
I think it's your repository must include the clear setup,
the instruction dependency or inputs or anything else or
commands for running the system.
And I think team should decide a solution to run on maybe
the standard CPU based environment. Okay. I think I should
not assume the GPU or the unrestricted internet access.
The unrestricted internet access will be available. I think
that will not provide private API key. I think team, you
all must not include the secret credential in the
repository and your repository and
your repository and how to say, external service only file,
you all should provide clear configuration instruction or
demonstration or anything else in
your readme file or in format of MDFI.
I think that may be run end to end to check your port, to
check your output. Yeah. I think this is all of my answer.
Thank you. Thank you, Achanthana. There's one more question
for you. It's about the evaluation environment. If the tool
will be executed, what infrastructure and constraints
should teams assume about CPU or GPU availability, internet
access, API key provisioning and expected runtime limits.
Please go ahead. Yeah, that I said, I think if you decide your code or your solution run on standard CPU based environment. Yeah. And I think if you should not assume that GPU or internet access will be available. Okay. And that I said that will not provide private
private API key. Okay. And that's more. Okay. I think your
solution should run on standard CPU
based environment. I think it's better. Yeah.
Thank you. Thank you so much. So that is, I think should
answer that question. I think that is all the questions we
have for the research and evaluation and the technology
process. Let's move on to questions about scope and
methodology. So the first few
questions, Gunmita, are there for you.
There have been questions about the indicator mapping
crosswalk. So the question is, is there an official
crosswalk mapping the methodology indicator codes from 6.1,
6.2, 7.1, 7.2 to the output template codes like P6, -i,
yeah, i1, P6, -i2. So is there any
official correspondence tables related to this?
So basically P6 mean PLA6 and i1 mean indicator one. So in
the data set that you were given, it would call indicator
6.1. So basically, you should
refer to P6 i1 as 6.1, P6 i2 as 6.2.
And if you want to see what are these indicator
descriptions, the best document that you have to consult is
the RDTI 2.1 framework documentation,
which is already in the knowledge portal.
And also the excels of the sample data sets that we give to
you for those three countries is also
official short name for these indicators.
Yeah, this brings us to the next question for their
submissions. Must the indicator codes follow the template
format or the methodology
codes like 6.1 versus P6 i1? Yeah.
What is the difference between
this question and the previous?
I guess it's a similar question that being that there is no
difference, but they can refer directly to our guides and
stuff. But will we score them differently if they follow
any of the other? Or is there a preference
from us for what indicator codes they follow?
Our preference would be follow the official documentation,
RDTI 2.1 framework documentation. But if you happen to use
P6 i1 as per the template that we give, and if you call to
the indicator description
correctly, you will not be penalty.
Yeah, so it seems like the source of truth, like the main
document should be the RDTI documentation that we have
given them, like guide and database
and all of the published documents.
Okay. There is another question about translation, and
maybe we should clarify this because I
also saw this question in the Q&A box.
So it says that the template requires verbatim snippet
entries without modification of paraphrasing, right? So for
non-English legal sources, should this field contain the
original text or an English translation? And if there is a
translation required, is it a designated translation source
or a tool that they need to use?
Yeah.
Now, verbatim snippet would mean exact quotation from the
official document. So if it is a country that has no
English official version, this column will quote the
original those non-English language.
But you need to add additional columns of verbatim English
as your additional columns append after
the 13 columns that we have given to you.
Okay.
Basically, verbatim snippet should have exactly as it says
in the document, and then they can add an additional column
with the English translation.
But some countries, they provide two versions, official,
two official versions. One is their local language. The
other one is English translation, official language. So in
that case, your verbatim snippet can
come from an official translation version.
Okay. Understood.
Now, let's move on to the question about the HSN codes and
the ICT products. So there seems to have been some
confusion about the coverage column, right? So in our
database, we capture how the entry,
which sector or which sectors it affects.
So the question in this case is that for the optional
pillars, must outputs explicitly include HSN codes for ICT
product classifications? If so, where should these be
recorded within the existing
template that we have provided?
If you are going to add those codes, which is not mandatory
in the list that we provide to you, you can add as the
additional column append to the end
of the matrix that we give to you.
So again, additional column is welcome as long as the data
is relevant, right? So coming down to again, the
classification rules. This is a question about known versus
new classifications. So how is the known versus new
designation determined? At the statue level, at the
provision level, at the URL
level, or the indicator mapping?
For example, if a statue appears in the sample kit, but a
newly identified clause does not, should
that row be classified as known or new?
New.
New. So even if it is...
Because it was not shown in
the matrix of existing evidence.
Right. So even if that particular law has been recorded by
us, but the tool managed to record a new provision, we will
still give it a new classification, basically.
Yes.
Okay. Now similarly to this, how are those classification
incorporated into the scoring? And should, for example,
treaty memberships on other non-domestic legal sources be
considered eligible for new
evidence or treated as out of score?
Basically. So I guess this question has two parts. One is
how the new or new classification would be incorporated
into the scoring criteria. And if they find new information
about treaty memberships or other international legal
sources, can they add it into that
output or it will be treated as out of score?
I think you have to check the criteria of the indicators.
If it is met with the criteria, then you can add as the
relevant evidence, but it might be new if we never record
it before. However, if the criteria say one thing which is
not relevant to the treaty
memberships, then your findings is out of score.
Right. In terms of scoring, I guess the, I would say like
the, it depends, right? Like what evidence they find and
then that evidence, the way it fits into the scoring
criteria will affect how it is
scored in the RDTI framework.
Yes. I feel that this question is
similar to the one that referred to 7.54.
Yeah. Yes, I would say so because there is a mention of the
treaty membership and like non-domestic legal sources. So
is it true that the teams are finding more information that
can be included in RDTI? Would we accept an output with
extra information or is it still out of score?
Sorry, can you repeat that? I
don't understand what you say.
So one of the questions we had before was also about if
they could, they found new information about international
treaties and they could add that information to the RDTI
output that that tool creates. Would we consider that out
of scope or would we score it
and it will be accepted basically?
But which indicator we are talking about then?
It would have to be the out of scope indicators basically.
So again, those out of scope ideas. Yeah.
Okay. Thank you so much, Kunvitada. I will move on to
Juntong for the next three questions.
So Juntong, one of the question is about how do it again
about like how we record certain data sets. So for
provisions that map to multiple indicators or indicators
supported by multiple provisions, what is the expected unit
of observation in this output?
Is it like one row per provision, one row per indicator or
one row per provision indicator pair? How would you record
multiple indicators to one provision basically?
Multiple indicators to one provision. You mean one
provision applies to multiple indicators? Then you just
insert each entry depends on which indicator you were
talking about. Like each one indicator, one entry.
Right. And what would you do in the case of one indicator
have multiple provisions or
laws or regulations attached to it?
I mean, like if they are considered as one measure because
like they ask us answering the same question, they're
answering the question. I mean, like they give the same
answer to this specific indicator question, legal question.
Then you just record, you can record them in one entry, but
with semicolon to separate each.
Sorry, can I say something? Yeah.
In terms of the output, you should make it as clean as
possible. So that would mean one entry, one provision.
Yes. Yeah. Can I say? Yeah, because I feel like probably
our participants is mixing up the assignment and the
submission output. The assignment for me is just a hands-on
practice just to let you know how the human
beings, how the human lawyers collect data.
So the structure I gave you, like the IDTR database
structure I gave you is like what we do with the human
lawyers. But for your first-round submission output, I
think Dr. Witadai has already introduced the output
template in the first session.
You should always use the one she gave to you, not the one
I gave you the assignment. It's a slightly different
structure. So if you deliver your
output, always use that template.
Yeah. So what I said, you can use semicolon to separate
different provisions. It is just for human lawyers, like
how we collect data. But for maybe the AI delivery output,
you need to refer to that template.
So what I'm getting is, of course, the way we did it
manually was different. And the point is that the output
just has to be clearly mapped. You just need to know
exactly which provision matters to
which indicator and how it applies.
Yeah, I just want you to get familiar
with how the legal research goes on.
Okay. In terms of the coverage of the provision, right,
could you clarify the intended treatment of sexual versus
horizontal frameworks, including whether horizontal
frameworks take precedence or for indicator 7.2
specifically in this case, and how
multiple sector law should be classified?
I mean, I have highlighted when I was in my second session,
like the authority or the power of the law does not depend
on if it's horizontal or sectoral. It only depends on who
authorizes this law, like who or what authorizes this law.
So it basically refers to the legal hierarchy. So it
doesn't matter if it's horizontal or sectoral. Like for
indicators 7.2, which refers to the cybersecurity law, and
if there is a dedicated cybersecurity legal framework, and
it applies horizontally, like apply to every sector.
And also there is a specific sectoral law where they have
some provisions on cybersecurity
protection, but it's not completely comprehensive.
But they are all, like in the legal hierarchy, like they
are all authorized by the Parliament, by the act. Like the
name is like cybersecurity act or let's say, broadcasting
act. And they all refer to the
cybersecurity, and they are all act.
And they are, they have the same legal hierarchy. So it's
not like the horizontal one overriding sectoral one or
sectoral one overriding the horizontal
one. It's like, it doesn't depend on that.
And for the multi sectoral law, I mean, if like we identify
this as as horizontal, only when
this law applies to all the sectors.
And I say, if there is a law refers to the financial and
the banking, like financial sector and banking sector, and
like they refer to two sectors, but we also see this as
sectoral law, because the only refer to the financial
sector and the banking sector
is just like, not all sectors.
So then we refer to this as a sectoral
law, not horizontal law in this case.
Okay, I think, yeah, I think this is a confusion that could
be solved by just reading legal text more and understanding
the scopes of different laws, I guess.
So, moving on to the scope of laws, really. So this is
specifically for indicator 7.5, and I
guess it can apply to other indicators as well.
The question is, should teams extend their review beyond
primary privacy legislation to other related laws like
criminal procedure or national security laws?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, sure. Of course, you need to extend
because we want our database to be as comprehensive as
possible. So I totally get it because about government
access personal data, sometimes
it's not just about data protection.
It also refers to the criminal law or criminal procedure
law. And as long as you can find the provisions in the
criminal law, criminal procedure law, that is related with
7.5, or this is the requirement on government accessing
personal data, then you should
record it because it's relevant.
Right. Okay, so we basically record everything that is
possible, as well as overarching laws in the country as
well, as long as it's relevant. Yeah.
Okay, so these were all the
questions we had related to school.
I saw a Q&A asking about sharing Excel workbook, so I hope
that you see my screen. It is the file of the output
template, which we give in a knowledge portal.
And we, if you refer to my presentations on the first day,
we have also indicate in the slide about
required columns with required metrics.
So, I guess the same person is also asking the question
that can we add additional columns or for other parameters?
We can, right? I think you must have mentioned that. Yes.
So you can add other columns for parameters that are
important to the data collection process, example, the
translated text or coverage, etc. Yeah.
Okay, actually, this actually brings me to the next
question, which is for exactly what you showed Koonvitada
about the, does the final deliverable need to follow a
format similar to the assignment
that Juntong gave in assignment 2?
Or may teams adapt the structure provided that all
information is included in that structure?
You asked me, can you repeat the question? Yes. The
question is basically, does the final deliverable need to
follow a similar format to what Juntong's assignment 2 had?
Or can teams adapt the structure as per what they require?
You cannot follow the assignment 3 structure. You have to
follow the output structure that we give it to you in the
actual on screen and it is in the knowledge portal.
Yeah, can I say I have to highlight it again because my
assignment is only for you to get familiar. It's not your
final submission output template.
So please go to the slides of orientation day, slide number
18. That's a structure output recommended field. So you are
Excel or your JSON or whatever you
produce need to have that required columns.
You can add additional columns beyond this required columns
is fine, but all those mentions in the
slides on structure outputs, it has to be there.
So line number 18.
Yeah. About the additional column, one of the questions
that we had was what specific information should be
included in the notes column and how
detailed should this information be?
Notes column is quite flexible. We don't provide limit on
what characters of notes columns. The objective of notes
column is to flag any unusual case
or any things that user needs to know.
For example, it should flags that this snippet is based on
an official translation or it flags that the snippet is
based on official bilingual document.
Or anything else that you think the user should be aware
of, concerned of, or be careful
so that that is your own judgment.
Okay, thank you for clarifying that. Now, the output
template, as we have discussed the output template must
follow what we have provided. This is
specifically to the documents we have provided.
The readme file indicates separate outputs per pillar. So
like p10.csv is a separate file per pillar, while the
output template for 31st May excel file consolidates
indicator 6 and pillar 6 and 7. For final submission,
should teams provide separate
files or use a consolidated template?
I think when you are still developing as a developer, it is
more simple to do it one by one because when anything is
wrong, you can just run on that
particular indicator, that country specifically.
But when you produce a final output for submission, you
just merge them into one consolidated file. Because you
have to decide your final output with user in mind, and you
have to be aware that the users, which is the policy or the
reviewers or researchers, it's much easier for them to go
through one file rather than multiple files.
And please be careful that we also reward your design of
final product with user in mind, especially in your final
route that will come into the matrix of evolutions.
I don't think it's very
complicated to just merge them at the end.
Yeah, I think all roads lead to the same destination in a
way. About the template, staying over there, just two more
questions about that. Is the location_reference column
required? Or is it optional? Because I guess we give
conflicting information because in the xlx, sx template, we
do say it's required and in the readme, we say it's
optional. So they're asking
for clarification whether it is.
When I check at my output template, location reference is
always optional. So I don't
know where they get it as required.
According to the question, it says that in the xl file that
we did provide, it does say required. But the conclusion is
that it is an optional. It is optional. I mean, when I
check the output template that I deposit in my file, it say
optional. And I confirm that it is optional.
Okay, and for the last question in this particular type of
question, for the last amended column, like the field,
should the granularity be month and year or just the year
is okay? So what is the granularity? Are we looking at take
month year, month year or just year period?
If the information is available,
month and year is better than just year.
Okay.
Can I comment?
Would you also prefer date?
No. Jintou is about to say something. Yeah, can I comment? Because when I was revealed the
submitted assignments, and I also found this kind of issues
that I think they might also encountered.
For the tab line column, what we prefer is like you the
format is since month year, like, and then last amended in
month year. This is the preferred format. But sometimes,
like, you can, like, you can, you just cannot confirm which
month, like you can only the only information you can find
is a year. Then in this case, you can just provide a year.
But as long as you have an accurate,
accurate month, then please month and year.
Yeah.
Okay. Okay. Thank you for clarification about this
particular column. So now I have two questions for Ajahn
Thanavit and Ajahn Atubu. These are related to the
submission process and the deadline itself. So what the
question is generally what is the
submission process for the 20th July deadline?
What is the platform? The format? What timeline is the
deadline is? Is it in Bangkok time? And whether the updates
are, whether you will allow the participants to update
their submission after the deadline has passed.
Yeah.
Okay. I will answer the first question is about how to
submit or submit all of that really required.
Okay. Actually, it is on the screen. It's the, like, it's
the our top prize for, for submit. And, okay. And how, how
you actually submit everything. Okay. Everything goes to the single online form, maybe on the third form that are formed that are formed that you submit on in the, for the destination to the
hackathon. Okay. One form and all four artifacts. Okay. And
you must submit all of that we require. The functional prototype, the structure output five and the technical pitch deck and the
Yeah, maybe the, the Liza video or the screen recording
work through in our platform. Okay. That we will send to
the link. Okay, the link for this platform, we will send to you later in maybe the, the link for the platform, we will send to you later in the, the, uh, the, uh, the link as it is.
we will send to you later in maybe the head of your team
email. Okay, we will provide the
form link for submission. Okay. And I
think the timeline, the submission timeline for
the first round on 20th July, maybe depend on Thai time,
right? Dr. Vitha, I'm not sure.
Yes. Bangkok time. Yeah, Bangkok time, right?
Yes. And did you cover about the
required formats and for the pitch deck and the
10 minute video, are there any
specific formats or file size limitations?
Where can we find this information and where can the
participants find this information?
Okay, I think I will provide all
information with the submission link form. Okay.
Okay. So I hope that clears up submission and output
related requirements for our participants.
Now we have some technical questions in
our question bank and I hope I can ask
Ajahn Thanavit and Ajahn Ratapul to answer these questions,
right? So the first question is about
the user input design. Will the users interact with the
tool through free text prompts or should
teams design structured inputs such as
country drop downs and indicator selectors?
I think the question is, can you repeat the
question? Sure, no problem. So the question
is about the input design, like how will users interact
with the tool itself? Will the users
interact with the tool through a free text prompt or should
teams design structured inputs such as
country drop downs or selecting mechanisms
basically? I think it's up to you because
I think our chat may have the criteria for input to check
the answer or check your output
for your solution. I think it's up
to you. Okay. Your solution may be
drop down or anything else. I think
it's okay because I think we will have
a solution to check your answer or your output. Okay.
The next question is also about the
interface of the tool that they make.
Is a command line interface or CLI required or a graphical
user interface like GUIs are also
acceptable? I think a command line
interface or CLI is not mandatory.
I think if you use the graphic user interface, GUI may
provide good usability and presentation.
Okay. But I think the CLI is not
mandatory and that I said is up to your solution.
It is specifically required by a technical instruction in
the repository or our submission
checklist. Okay. Or you use bot CLI and the GUI I think are
acceptable. You may provide a CLI,
a web-based interface or like API or notebook interface.
Actually, I think it's up to your
solution. Okay. But you need to provide the readme file,
the MD file. Okay. And I think when you
submit, you must combine everything into the single
repository like GitHub or anything else
that can read your MD or readme
file and run your solution. Yeah.
May I add something? Yes, please.
The beautiful design user interface is not required in this
route, but it will be required
in the final round. So until then, you are free to do
whatever but document it in a
structured way that we can clone
and replicate what you did to test.
Thank you so much for clarification.
Now, the next question again for technical,
it's about the web search approach, basically. And the
teams are asking should teams prioritize
official APIs and third-party search
services instead of direct web scraping?
Do we have a preference basically for any of these methods?
Who do you ask? I guess I can start with Dr. Tanavit and
then Kumbhata or Dr. Dattakum,
if you want to add anything. I think
the question is about the prioritize between official API
or third-party search instead of
direct web scraping, right? Yes, the question is like that.
Do you want me to answer? Okay, Dr.
Vithada, maybe answer this question.
We don't prohibit you from using third-party but please
note that one of the evaluation criteria
is cost efficiencies. If the third-party
application add to the cost, then that would
affect somewhat to the evaluations.
Yeah, actually my answer, I'm not sure
because maybe in the context of the leak or maybe
shame, but actually in my opinion, I
think if you can build your solution,
that Dr. Vithada said, if you can save
your cost or you can build the third-party but
can install in your local repository or your server and can
save your cost and the output
is have a good efficiency, I
think maybe better for your solution.
Okay, understood. So the teams have to basically make a
decision based on the best approach of
their tool and their design, etc. Basically, I mean,
productivity is an cost efficiency.
Yeah. Okay. And similarly, we have a
question about the document ingestion part.
The question was, can existing PDF documents be ingested
into the vector database for retrieval
and querying? I guess there is a lot to
be said about this. So Dr. Vithada or Ajahn
Tanavit, any one of you can
start. Whoever is ready to answer.
I think if you came to the workshop session on the past, in
the 12th, I think Dr. Ratashai or the
another professor, they talk about
the detail, how to ingest the document,
maybe like a rack or anything else. Yeah, I
think, yeah, if you follow the solution that
what professor provide to you, I think you can know the
detail, how to ingest the document,
how to work with the vector database or anything else. Dr.
Vithada, maybe add more details.
I just want to add that once you ingest
the files, check it and save it. It's okay,
but you need to have the system that you
can track, monitor any new documents that you
coming after you already download an interest because in
any times or any days coming,
there might be additional evidence released. Yeah, I agree.
So basically for the existing
PDF documents that we already had, they can be used, but
there is a scenario in which countries
go ahead and update their laws or they repeal them or they
make, they cancel their notifications.
So in that case, like Kumbhutada said, you will have to
have a system in which you need to find
a way to update the existing repository of documents we
have. Okay. I just wanted to go
back to one of the questions I asked.
I'm not sure if it was answered actually,
about updating the submissions. I'm sorry if I didn't hear
Ajahn Thanavik if you answered this,
but the question was like, can the participants update
their submissions after they have
submitted and the deadline has passed?
I think I'm just trying to allow until the, to resubmit,
right? Until their live or not.
Sorry, can you repeat the
question? The question is basically,
can the teams update or change their submissions after they have submitted and the deadline has
passed? No, because we once they submit, we will have to
start reviewing it. And if they
change, then we will never end the process. Okay.
Okay.
I see one more question in my list before maybe we can move
on to some live questions if you want.
But there is one question about what is
the expected time budget per evaluation run?
Is it in minutes or hours?
So I guess I can ask this to Koonmata if you can start and
then maybe Professor Ajahn can,
sorry, Ajahn can get to go. I get what I'm not following.
The time budget. So they're asking for
the evaluation runs. Is there an expected?
What do you mean time budget? In the sense, how much time
should every evaluation run take?
Are we expecting it to run in minutes
or are we expecting it to run in hours?
For one country?
For how many countries we are
talking about and how many indicators?
Yeah, I don't think they have clarified in this question,
but let's say one country or maybe the
existing country. I think I'm reluctant to say what exactly
would be the time estimated because
if the system that you decide is making it a reasonable
fast, that would be score high.
If you are slow, then efficiency score will be lower. But
yeah, so this is a competition.
So give it fast as much as you can. Yeah. So as fast as
possible, it would be the name of the case.
And maybe we'll see who is the fastest
and more accurate, more evidence as well.
Yeah. Okay. So I think we have, I have asked you all the
questions that I had in my list.
Would you be open to taking live
questions from Q&A box? Do we have time?
We have like 15 to 20 minutes. Okay, I think we can go
through them until the time is enough.
Okay, so let me just take a quick look at one of the
questions I had found before.
So one of the question is during the
presentation, during the submission,
should we have a real working prototype or
a description of the, and sorry, during the
presentation, we should show a real working
prototype and a description of the product
itself, right? That's a question that we have received.
This is referring to live demo presentation interview.
So it says during the presentation,
if Azizim could clarify, then maybe
I could bring it back to you
basically. But basically in principle,
yes, make your prototype
working and ready for straight case.
Okay. You will be interviewed
and showing your product live.
Okay, so there's a question from Mohammed and it's a follow
up on the question that Juntung answered
about the scenario where one provision is at the law level
and then the follow up detailed provision
is regulated at a law under it. So one provision is at the
higher law level or at the act level,
maybe is that if that's what they mean, and the detailed
provision is more at a lower than act
level hierarchy. And they're saying in the RDTI database,
there is one example of this in the
Indonesian health law. And then there's a follow up that is
in the regulation of the health.
In this case, is it recommended to
combine it into one row or recorded separately?
Where basically asking if two regulations
feed into each other and inform each other,
should they record it together or
should they record it separately?
I think maybe Juntung if you
could answer this question for us.
Yes. Yes, how about this is right. So I mean, RDTI
database, I'm just saying like the manual
data collection process. In this case, we will record this
to the upper hierarchy and the lower
hierarchy and the same entry. But as Dr. Waitada said, like
in order to make your output template
clean, then we prefer to have
one entry for one provision, right?
Yes. And then make use your node column to explain the
cross reference and the hierarchy of these
two laws. Yeah, you can document them in
different roles, but next to each other
and put the nodes explain that these two laws are working
together and what would be the implications.
Yeah, so for the manual process, you can
put it together. But I mean, for the output,
then just do whatever you were requested to do. Okay. Okay,
I think you've answered this question.
There is a question about evaluation. For the evaluation
techniques that we'll use, will we
test against our full known provision sample kit or a
subset of it? So I guess they're asking like,
will we make sure that they have found every single
provision and law that we have found,
or are we okay if they only find a
subset of those laws and provisions?
I guess this is a question about efficiency, whether they
need to find everything we have
already found, or should they, are they,
I'll be okay with the tools finding just
a little bit of what we have already found. Yeah.
We will test against the full known evidence. Okay, so we
will always compare against the
full known evidence. Yeah. And beyond, if
they can find something we have. Yes, the
object is you found more than what
we found, not less than what we found.
Yeah. It is an interesting question about source validation
and URL links. Should the tool detect
and flag broken URLs and repeat laws automatically, or it
should be noted separately in the documentation?
So question to ask, I'm not following. Okay, so they're
asking basically, what are tools? Should
the tool be able to tell us whether there is a broken URL
or the law has been repealed automatically,
as part of the output, like when they give us that output
in the framework that we have asked
them to, or is it something that should go into the notes
column or should be documented separately
in a different part of the output? I think
because we don't have the column that shows
how the status like broken URL, or repeal laws. So I think
what you can do is you have to use
notes column. I mean, if the law is also repealed, then we
don't record it because we also record only
active laws, right? So in that case, there is also a
scenario where they might find a law that is
repealed, then I don't think you'd record it. If they
happen to record it, but they mark it
correctly that it is repealed, we are
okay with it. But if they record it,
if they record repeal law, and they don't say that it is
repealed, it would imply that this law is
still active, then it's become a wrong
evidence. You will be penalized for that.
Right. Okay. So always record active laws
and the ones that are still operational.
Yes. If you happen to file a law, and you know that it is
repealed, and you want to keep it for
prudential reasons or something, fine, but put it clear in
the notes or as additional columns of
the status. Right. Okay. This is a question about can teams
use the anthropic plot for legal plugin
as a base framework? Or must
the tool be built from scratch?
Teams can use whatever as long as you build it in the
architectures that satisfy our
conditions of it is flexible to be swapped between modules.
Right. Okay. I think, okay, I think I'm going to direct.
Oh, I see. I think I'm already
answered it right as I was about to ask it. Okay. And in
terms of in a scenario, when there is no
legal or relevant law found for an indicator, how should
they record it? Should they just leave
a blank row or should they just, yeah,
just not record it at all for that indicator?
In case that a team happens to find in this scenario, no relevant law or regulation,
for an indicator, what should they do in that scenario? You
should put a mark of no evidence,
no provision found, something like that. Don't make it
anything because it's not clear.
But I guess there's also something to be said about not
finding any evidence, right? Like in a
lot of cases when we do manual research, we also record
laws where we didn't find evidence in.
So for example, this is just an example about data
protection. This is just an example laws exist for
this. If for example, a researcher finds that there is no
such law for data protection,
they will go to the data protection act and
find that there is no such law and they will
also record the absence of a law. So I think getting that
is more valuable than because it
shows that you have looked over just leaving it empty, I
guess. Yeah. No, no provision found.
Because if you leave it empty, we don't know what does it
mean. I could interpret that this is
file or something. Yeah. Okay.
There's one really long question,
which I just need a quick second to summarize.
And that is a short question that asks for sharing again
the output templates. So this,
the secretary after the meeting, maybe send out an email or
indicate where these key documents are.
I can also tell you now it's in the knowledge portal and it
should be in the sample kit or one
of those folders as well. So if you don't already have
access to knowledge portal, please let us
know by now and we can give you access for it basically.
Yeah. Okay. So let's start with the
first half of that question. Could you clarify the expected
testing and interaction workflow
for the final evaluation of a prototype? So specifically,
will the judges evaluate a system
in a document by document mode where we give them, where
the tool is given every single URL or a PDF
and then it extracts the information and the score from it?
Or are we expecting them to give
a fully automated batch batch processing mode where we give
it all the data, all the files,
and it gives us every single IDT indicator for that
particular country all at once. So do we expect
them to give us one by one, like we give it a file and it
gives us an output or for one indicator or
one country, or do we want them to batch process where we
give them all the documents we have,
like the tool, and then the tool gives us all the answers
all at once. They're asking this
question because they want to define the exact boundary of
a human in loop and front end and
our automatic back end pipeline. I'm not sure who to ask
this question to be really honest. Maybe
our KM colleagues could help us
with this particular question. Yeah.
Can I say something? Yeah. When we test your tools, right,
we will have to do the document
by document testing because we will have to test whether
your specified URL really exists and is
active or not. And we will also test whether the refer
document really exists and what you are
providing the interpretation is correct based on the
indicator criteria or not. So I think document
mode, if you refer to that context to
facilitate human in loop is preferred.
But if a team can do a good job with batch
processing mode, is that a limitation of any
cause or like? But by the end, I mean, there is a state of
review the products and there is a state
of after review, it is confirmed products so that your tool
has to prove it is end to end
automations after you have done, you have passed through
the process of human verifications of your
product first. Okay. So that is the last of our questions.
We made a way through all of them.
Maybe I can give a final. I think Ajahn Tanavith has
something to show for the last 10 minutes.
If you would like to show it now or
would you like to wait a little bit longer?
Yeah, actually, I will present maybe
just a recap. Again, maybe a recap.
What you need to deliver or submit to us and the timeline
for our hat on and how to submit.
Okay, I will share the slide. But
actually, this slide that I share is
it's the same as the slide that we provide to you in
orientation. Yeah, I will recap again in.
Yeah, I will share my slide.
Okay.
Yeah, we can see it. Yes. Okay, you see the slide, right?
Yes, we can.
Okay.
Okay. Then I said, okay, what does submit mean? Okay, we
need your five deliverables, right?
Okay, let me be specific. Okay, there are five
deliverables, right? Okay, four of them you upload
by the 20 of July. Okay, and the
20 teams that we select. Okay, maybe
live demo on the third of August. Okay. And the key
requirement that you need to deliver
was to submit on 20 July. First, that I said, first is the
functional prototype. Okay, you
should submit like the link of your GitHub or your
repository. Okay, including the script API
or anything else that can run your script or file or the
doctor email file or anything else.
Okay, that make sure that we can
read your read me five or you maybe
display in the read me five or the MD five. Okay, that and
then when we read your read me five,
we can like set up environment or anything else. Okay, and
run your solution like an end to end
solution. Okay, and show the output. Okay, and the output
on Yeah, maybe that on the application
or the output or maybe export to CSV or JSON file or
anything else. And next is the structure output
file case you need to submit your CSV and JSON file that we
provide to you in KM. Okay, that
from this slide on the orientation, okay, I think I will be
presented to you already. Okay, what
the column that we require what the column what a column
that is optional. Okay, and the
sign by that we need to know from you. And next is the
Okay, is the submission timeline. Okay,
here is all of our timeline to the day to life. Here is the
deadline for submission. Okay,
and next question is okay. How to how you actually submit?
Okay, actually, I answer to you in
some of question that that you that you asked in the live
Q&A. Okay, I will confirm again.
Everything okay that you need to submit with everything
goes to a single single online form
like the chart form. Okay, that form is a form that
application form that you register to
to join this hackathon competition. Okay, but the link,
okay, the platform link we will
send to you later. Okay, at the at the latest, I think
maybe in next week, okay, we will send to
your, your email, your email in each team, maybe the head
of team email. Okay. And I think in
in detail, okay, we will, we will send the
another detail in attached with this email,
okay, with with the submission link to you later. Okay. And
31st July, we will announce the
20 shortlist to live pitch on third August. Okay. And I
think the fifth August maybe announce the
the teams, the five teams to maybe come to Bangkok in the
finale round. Okay. Okay, I think
yeah, it's all of my presentation that
detail about it, how to submit and what
that need from you to submit.
I'm not sure after we did that, maybe
have any detail for talk with the audience.
Well, I think you have captured it.
Well, let me check is that there is one more
questions in the Q&A. Yes. Okay, yes.
How are we expected to measure the OCR,
CR if there is no manually verified ground truth text?
Oh, I think you can go with that. If
you can answer this. I'm also thinking.
What do you mean by that is no
manually verified ground truth text?
So I think in a scenario where, for example, if there is,
if they find something that we don't
have in our data set, and we have not verified it and told
them that this is the ground truth,
because you have to provide us the URL
that you found, right? So from that, you
will be tracked to document that you are referring to and
compare it with what you are extracting
from the document. I think that and I guess they're talking
also about like OCR, like probably
reading like an image PDF, but in that case also, they will
have to do some of their own checks
as we do when we manually data collect as well. We
translate it, we try to understand if it actually
makes sense or not. And if it actually makes sense for the
indicator itself. So before they even
submit to us, if, for example, they find something that we
haven't recorded, or they can't verify
against our database, I think it requires a little bit of
like going through it themselves as well.
Right? Yes, you have to provide us the inputs that you scan
and extract takes that you did.
So we will compare it and evaluate your code. You can
evaluate from that. And you can flag it in your
node columns where his OCR is has an issue or something.
Okay, yes. I don't think we have any
more questions in the Q&A. I have been asked by the admin
to tell to announce that the link to the
submission portal will be sent to send by email to all
participants around the submission deadline.
So you should have it in your inbox closest to 20th June.
Yes. I want to give Dr. Vethada,
Ajahn Thanavit and Ratpum a minute to make any last
comments. Anything you would like to say
to our participants before the big deadline
comes by. Yeah, I just want to wish everyone
good luck. And please send us questions in email if you
have problems or something that you think
of classification needs. Yes,
and we will get back to you. Yeah.
Ajahn Ratpum, Ajahn Thanavit, do you
have any words for our participants?
Ajahn Thanavit, yes. I think the key that is really
important and I think Dr. Thawit,
my KMIT outside, I think maybe we will provide the job form
for your submission very early,
okay, as fast as possible. Okay. And we'll send to you
again by email because 20 July is just only
five days for me. No, not five
days. This is June, right? 20th June?
July or June? I'm not sure. Oh, July,
sorry. Sorry. I'm confused. Okay, again,
again. July. Okay, next week, next
week. Okay. Okay. Next week is happy enough,
Sarah. Okay. 20 July, not 20 June. Okay.
Yes. Yeah, I think I'm not sure how to say.
Okay, I think we will look for how to say the clear and
work prototype. I think if you
make your solution easy to
understand, easy to test and evaluate, okay, and
you'll provide a clear output, okay, and the data or the
symbol of your setup, your end
development, I think it's better to
you to get the high score, I think.
I will say, okay, thank you for your
attention. We look forward to seeing your
innovation, your idea, your prototype to help the SCAN or
help the UN team or ask here to
find a new solution for the law
or the regulatory or anything else.
Jake, I think I would like to say good luck to your teams.
Hope you enjoy this challenge. Yeah.
I think what I can say is important in terms of whenever
you decide your output files,
your backend files, always have your target user in mind.
You have to facilitate the review.
You have to facilitate their use because
that is affecting the value of your products.
If you make the products excellent, but no one can easily
use, then it becomes useless.
Thank you so much to three of you
for your words of wisdom. Thank you,
Jungdong, for also answering the questions that the
participants have had. I'm again going to
wish you all the best and all of the luck for your tool
designs and thank you for your participation
and staying with us for the past two
weeks, and we will see you guys soon, hopefully,
at least by 20th July when we see your submissions. Thank
you all and have a good evening. Bye-bye.
Bye-bye. Thank you very much. Thank
you. Thank you so much. Goodbye. Bye.