Hello everyone and welcome. Thank
you for tuning in to today's webinar.
Tonight is the final day of the Open Workshop session and
on Monday we have wrap-up session
for the Hackathon Survivors for the next round competition.
I am Ratapul Baliyat Bisha from
School of Engineering, Kim Kuk-in-Sih of Technology, Laka
Bang. I am the moderator of webinar today.
If you have been following the AI space, you know that
documents AI and IHE or retrieval
augmented generation are absolute game changers right now.
But how do you actually build these
two chains and what does the development, the deployment
architecture look like in the real world?
That is exactly what we are breaking down today in our
session, Document AI and Lecture
Chains and Deployment Architecture. We have a fantastic
line-up today with two billion
minds who are the forefront of engineering
education and research. Let's welcome Dr.
Shen Chiu, Professor of Engineering at Maynooth
International Engineering College.
And also we have my colleague Dr. Latachi
Shau-Wu Tai, Professor of Engineering from School of
Engineering, Kim Kuk-in-Sih of Technology, Laka Bang.
Professor Latachi is the first speaker today. He is now
leading in expert data analytics and software
engineering, specializing in semantic
web technologies and knowledge management.
He brings extensive international research
experience from the National Institute of
Informatics in Japan, focusing on link-open data and data
visualization. Please give a warm welcome
to Dr. Latachi. Okay, Dr. Latachi, now the floor is yours.
Okay, thank you, Dr. Latachi.
I can say that good evening from Bangkok. Maybe you are
allowed to go, right? Maybe say hello to
all of you. Okay, I will share this. I
send that URL of my slide into the chat box.
You may exit that one.
I think that you may see my sharing. Yes, sure.
Okay, let's start. This one is about the knowledge
workshop. I'm Latachi Shau-Wu Tai,
who is working on this topic, SCAP-XM2L with the knowledge
workshop. Maybe I will start with that.
Sorry. I'll introduce myself first. I'm Latachi Shau-Wu Tai
from Computer Engineering. I finished
PhD from the second day in Japan. My work has about five
years working at PILENZ at the
Thomson Reuters in Thailand and at Pansan Asia. For my few
of today's slides, it's about AI
machine learning and the last-located model and something
else about the GPS, data analytics,
software engineering and some synthetic technology. Okay,
maybe we'll start with today's three topics,
generative AI, LMS and that.
First, I will talk about generative AI.
I think that right now you know already that the AI can
produce anything, right? Like any content.
The input can be anything like a text, voice or image and
image together with the video.
Okay, and this becomes a problem. And then inside the model
right now is the neural network that
has the architecture of deep learning.
And it's produce that output like a text,
image or audio or video as you need.
This one is not new right now. Okay,
many people talk about this and use this product around the
world. Okay, and as you know that,
for the main things of the generative AI, they are about
the tech generation that you'd
form the chativity from the Gemini and Crot something else
and the image generation and audio
and video and the best one is we can
produce the code, the programming programming code
from the generative AI. That's why we can
make any software from the human prompt.
This one is about the generative AI. I think you know
already, but I need to recall a little bit.
And then under the generative AI that produce the text and
code inside is the LM or the last
language modules. This one is a different example from the
professor Andrew. He said that example
this example that okay, start with that when we input this
one, my first foot is it and and
pass to the error module and return the vehicle. And after
that the vehicle becomes input again
and this produce the width. And after that, the width
becomes the input again and then it's
produced a cream and once the cream becomes the input
again, it produces the chest and it produces
the next word until the end of
sentence. This one is inside a language module.
And for the language module, I think that
you may know that the natural language of NLP
is start many years before and then for the every word that
we mentioned that it changed to the
vector start from this year 2013. That's because of our
word to work, change the human word
to the vector. And after we pass to that era of the neural
network like in N, F, C, M and
attention and until 2017, it become the transformer. At
that time, the world changed a lot.
And at this time, the AI module can produce any contents
and many, many modules produce after
that until now and become the era of the AI agent. Inside
the module, we talked a little bit about
this. Inside the module is about a metamatix. Here is some
example that I want to show you.
For example, when we have the input like this,
it's changed the input that has the human
word into the token vector like this one.
And after that, we have the
transformer module, including a lot of metrics.
We have the many, many layers and inside each layer, they
have the many kind of metrics layer
that are key and value until they do
like this, until they produce the output.
It means that the AI that we know is
just about the metrics inside the AI module.
Here is about the AI we talked
about looking to that inside the module.
And after that, we talked a little bit about the chatbot.
As you know, when we have the last run-read module that can
produce the contents from the user
prompt, we can use this thing to make a chatbot like this
one. For example, when we have the
chatbot application here, we have mobile application, web
application, only thing application,
and we use to submit the question to the chatbot like this.
And the chatbot will change this thing
into the prompt. And this prompt becomes the input to the
last run-read module. And then the LAM
generate the answer and the chatbot forward the answer to
user. This is just like a simple chatbot
that we use at the moment. But the problem is the module
doesn't train every day. It means that
when one is trained, the new knowledge, they don't
understand the new knowledge. That's why for some
time, they don't know the some word like this one. As I
added LAMAT 3.2, it's about 3 billion. I think
that this one is this built two years before. I asked that,
what is CE-KMTL? CE-KMTL is my department.
It's the username of my department, computer engineering
from the Kim Good Institute of
technology like a bank. And then one, the answer is CE-KMTL
or the College of Engineering. This one
is not correct. That's why we have to make the module
smarter. Another way that they use the
5 tuning. This one 5 tuning, they try to change the weights
or the number in the matrix to answer
the new question. This one, they have to have a lot of
documents that contain the question and answer.
And then they try to confirm to put to to to to change that
some matrix inside the module
until they can answer the new question. Here is example of
the data like this. They have the
instruction input and output layer, identify the full name
of the of this chart name. The input is
what is CE-KMTL and the output is the department. This is
the thing that we need to to train this
one by using this data, the department of computer
engineering from Kim Good Institute of Technology
like a bank. And this one is good. Last one or two years
before we are right in the world,
we will try to do this. But the problem is, and then
another example layer for medical domain.
Further provide the name of the drug.
For example, the input is the question for
I have the new headache and output
that you choose. Consider taking the
ibuprofen this form the medical domain. And this one, the
problem is that to do the 5 tuning,
we need a lot of resource like the big GPU
because we say that it's really expensive.
That's why the world come to
another solution by using the IHG orac.
For the IHG, I stand for the Retrieval Augmented
Generation. This one is the process
to make the LM module to answer the question based on the
incoming document without training
the module. We don't need to retain the module again. It
means that the process obtaining is
cheaper. But our work is try to manage the knowledge bit. I
will show some examples here.
Further like the challenge of the including is for the LM,
it may present for information.
The LM only they may present our update information. Maybe
it can create hallucination data.
Further like they can show this. This
one is the overall architecture of the IHG.
This form the application here. When the question from the
application go to the chatbot application.
Chatbot application we call that
is layer backend service or API.
The chatbot application convert this into the vector.
I should go back to the original thing. Before this for
people said we have many documents here.
A lot of documents here and we need to gather the text from
the document into the small chunks.
And then every chunk we have to
convert every chunk into the vector.
By using the some kind of embedding module. Right now I use
the BGM3. I will show you in the demo.
And put this one in the vector database. For the vector
database it's not the final solution.
But right now many people use the vector database. But you
can use any kind of database that can
answer the question from the user. And further like right
now we have a lot of data including
the vector and text vector and text vector and text. When
the user submit the question to the
chatbot. Again we have to query the proper answer from this
one. But in the in the in the
mathematic things we have to convert the question into the
vector by using the same module.
Like this one the same model the same
AI module to convert it to the vector.
And then we need to find the stimuli vector.
You can choose any number of of of of of the answer like a
top k like a top 10 top 5 or top 20.
It depends on you. It depends on the system. This one you
the developer can can config.
And right now okay one one for example we we get that the
files the file the file are answered from
this. This one will receive the contact clarify answer. And
after that the problem including the
question and the answer from the vector database. It's not
the pre-op question. It's not only the
question but include this one. And then the LM will answer
that will keep the answer to the user
based on this question and the answer the answer we call
the retic context. Like this one got get
the response to the user. It means that we can use the all
the out to date the out data if they
don't know the answer is okay but the answer is here.
That's why the model is just try to
rearrange the answer into the human friendly things.
This one is the main main issue of the RHE. We can
summarize this one. The first one maybe the
the pre-poset is try to convert the text from the many
documents into the vector data.
Try to give us a more strong optics and
change it to the vector data. It means the
vector database contains the vector and the text. And we
can say that which one becomes the
knowledge base. If we say the knowledge base can anything
can be vector database can be graph
database can be rational database or can be no QL data. It
depends on that. If we say that
don't base it better. And the step first step step one user
send the question to the chatbot
application. And the chatbot application change the human
question into the vector by using the model.
And then this part is the answer like five answer, ten
answer or 12 answer something like this
to the chatbot. And after that chatbot will set the new
problem including the question and the
relative context to the LAM. And LAM will rearrange the
response into the humanly able thing to the user.
The reason that we still need LAM is that
this one is not easy to read. It may be the
formal word from the local documents. And LAM help to
rearrange this into the smooth and easy to
create to the user based on the question.
We can say that the good system or black it depends on this
one. If we have a good knowledge base
nobody can answer the correct thing. The
black system will give the correct answer.
But we use the LAM for the real end that takes only.
After that for the term RAG, it is
one. For the term RAT4, it is one.
Littable is this. Just try to get the answer from the
knowledge base. This one is the Littable step.
For the A augmented is about the augmented problem by using
the RIT answer or the context.
This one the augmented. And then the generation is LAM
generated respond to the user
this is a generation step. That's why we call it RAG.
And as I say to improve that the system we have to improve
this thing. The way to process the
document into the knowledge base this is the critical thing
that you have to do in order to
make the precise system. And for the LAM
model I can say that sometimes this one
it will fix that okay it's five answer. The in the five
answer maybe sometime they have the
three answer and the other two maybe not the event. But
only only three three answer events.
The good LM can help you to filter the
good answer the correct answer to the user.
This one it helps to have you use the
power of LM. If we use a small LM the small LM
just the small M they try to conclude this thing into the
answer. That's why maybe it's
included channel in good noise. And if we use the good
enough LM they try to select only the
little one one to the user. It means that we cannot use any
LM we need to good enough LM.
For example right now I use the quin maybe
30 billion this one is a sort of good one.
Or the new one maybe you can use Gemma
for 12 billion right now. I didn't use
maybe I hope that it may be the good
one to be the candidate for the LM.
Okay here I did the document step
we have the problem pair like this.
This one the problem pair like this. Use the following
context to answer the question below
the context is here. This one is the list of answers that
we got from the knowledge bed.
And then we say that the question is
this this one is the neutral question
and we put the answer colon in order
to make the M to answer the question.
Or sometimes we can make more fancy from
like this. You are an expert in architectural,
you are expert in medical domain, you are expert in the
the Lego about the export something like that.
And answer the following question in the
language. Give some like a Thai language,
English language or some other language else. And then do
the same thing just put the answer here,
the list of answer here and put
the question from the user here.
For example here if you are you are expert in food please
answer the question in English
and then this one and and I can say that okay keep the
answer only to let the LM to keep the answer
only. And this one use the only
provide contact with this one basic.
Better this one the key feeling is about it one cook a hot
grill flip carefully and top it something
like this and I got when I can finish cooking the Japanese
and this and the LM will try to
analyze this and keep the answer that
corresponding to the question from the user.
This thing we get from the knowledge bed and after that
this problem will submit to the LM
and LM will be will answer I will
show some example like this one.
We just try to use from any LM like this
one just copy this problem and try to maybe
go to some LM layer chat GPT and
put this problem into the chat GPT
and based on this the LM will answer this.
You can finish the cook when that both
side are golden brows something like this.
And I will show you another example another
example is this one if I if I only this one
it can be this one I will go to another application like a
typhoon typhoon is the Thai LM.
I put that who donated land to my university.
The answer is the land of KMTL
it donated by the king Pupi Poon.
King that the former king this one is not correct okay this
one is not correct but after I
use the IHG system after I use the IHG system like this one
you are expert in KMTL please
answer the following question in English and this one you
contact like this one is held by the
memorial to japa ya sugo waya what something I did jokun da
haan and a lot of things okay
and I give this information to the LM.
Give this information to the LM.
And the answer is Miss Liam.
This one is the correct one this uh
this lady donated land to the KMTL.
That's why the leg become the powerful
when the LM is not smart enough okay.
And next I will go to the vector
database for the vector database is about uh
the first time we need to change every
sentence every product up into the vector.
For the vector they have a word emitting like I is changed
to vector one we change the vector
two change the vector after that they conclude the vector
into the one single vector like this one
we have a lot a lot more there and to
find that this time with a win vector
they have many will have a few ways the
first one this one is the token vector
you can you can look at the vector to the dimension like
this one is that word cat word tiger and word
fish. While we use the even by the UK
this time the cat and feet they hold together
but cat and tiger they are the cat is far
from tiger but if you another one like close
side this time we check at the ankle right now the cat is
close to tiger based on the ankle
and the cat is far from fish made on the ankle. In your
term you have to choose the proper one
you can understand or the whole side is done you can check
the model if the model is trained from
the whole side is done you choose the whole side is done if
the model they train from the UK
understand you have to choose the UK understand once my
student one of my students they use the
UK understand and they said a lot of incorrect answer I
asked them to share to the whole side
and after that it become the correct answer
it's based on the model but I can say that
a lot of model they use the close side is done. Here is the
vector database like this one we have
a lot of text chunks and use the embedding model and change
the text this one is one chunk two
chunk three chunk four chunk and n chunk and then this is
an example of that vector and this one is
a chunk of data in the human readable text this one is a
text vector and text vector and text
and after that when the user ask something this one is the
example operation in the text
we pass to the embedding model again and it change to the
vector and after that we go to the creative process
and this one is fine the cross vector the technical
crossing to this that's why they answer this and this
we do the top n with the text and you
can choose anything like top five top ten
top twenty it depend on you or even on your application
uh I'm familiar with this model VTM3 as I still use it
because VTM3 is a train for the question and answer
and it's not too big and it can say that it's multi-link
worth you can work with many uh many
language
and then here is some except something inside the VTM3 but
I want to show much about that
and we can say that we can we can
train retain the VTM3 by yourself yeah
okay we have a little bit time to
go to the hand on uh with the search
when you have to lie you can you can go to this example
this one example in the google so
I will keep you in the zoom again
where is zoom actually
um
uh h e demo and then I go back to that
I go back to that uh to the to my slide again
yeah when you click this let me go to this one
uh sorry right now it's not connected uh once you open this
please uh you you you cannot edit
anything but if you want to edit something you just go to
the file and then save a copy in your drive
and after this you can edit this one and then I recommend
you to change the GPU to the T4
because this one is you need to work with the GPU okay I
start from import something first
and then I uh download the model VTM3 here
we need to wait a little bit uh
because the VTM3 is about two two gigabytes
and after uh after that I I I made that in uh emitting
function input is take and the output
is the vector like this one and then I implement the cosine
similarity input is the vector a and
vector b and the output is the the cosine similarity and
first one I try to check that
okay the third vector is about uh the word character city
type capital city this one is the first one
and then I show the example vector of this one
the lens of vector is about one oh uh
1024 this this is because of the the
mvgm3 when we use change to another model it may be
different for example the gpt2 is about 768
for the llama maybe uh bigger than this
twice okay here is example of the third vector
for the second vector is a bankok the third vector is tesla
and then I check the whole side really
between the capital city of thai line and bankok
that's the symmetry is about 0.6
one we try to check with the capital
city of capital city of thai and the tesla
it becomes lower like this one it means that we can believe
that uh the vector the the uh the
sentence to work something like this and then I try adding
the data this one is I I got the data
about the the rule in the exam room like all this might be
completely something like this
I put this in the uh vector database uh in the data bed
like this one right now I use the pandas
this one is simple one okay in in your in your work you
have to use another thing not this one
you have to use some real production like a pikone or uh
open source uh vector database or something
else and this data are there are 10 documents here and
after that I try to embed in vector into the
every text into the vector wait a little
bit okay and check the data right this one
this one you text and this is the
vector text and vector take a vector
like this
and this is the the way to uh the function to query the
query is I I try to uh I try to get that
I try to get that uh real in that the answer from the the
high the the really close answer to the
uh to the last one for example when I add that can student
submit before half hour okay sorry
can student submit before half hour it show this one Italy
alliance again the first answer is no
student allow to leave the exam room
during the first 30 minutes something like this
it depend on this
vector and this vector
once you change the question for example
uh can student uh put take a cow creator
uh take a cow creator
it's made the alliance to something
else okay can student bring a smart boss
it become this one
okay every chain two and uh uh can see
can student submit before half an hour
the answer become this this one we have to believe the the
world the the vector space okay
and after that uh I use the IH but
right now for the more they're like a
for sure we have to download the model but right now I use
the Gemini service like this one
if you need this one you have to file
your Gemini key and put the Gemini key here
put the Gemini key and here you have to
file your Gemini key by yourself okay and put
Gemini key here and I try to check that Gemini is working
or not by acting at what is the
capital city of Thailand it answer that man called it's
okay and after that I try to uh make that
function for getting the LML so like this one get our MDS
spawn and then we put that question here
and I hope that it show the answer like
this one one if we as I check that okay
if we say hello world the Gemini will
answer this one hello there something like this
and after that I create the prompt template like this one
you are as AI model as done your
expert in answering the question with the national tone
answer the question based on the
foreign context the contact is here original question is
here this one is the function that I made
it is I have to check this one okay if I have the user
question here and the list of
contact for the vector db here the prompt become this this
one is a list of contact for the vector
db and this one is the user question okay after we apply
everything we go to the query
the question is user question is can
students submit before sorry before half an hour
and then I set the top three lists out like this one just
check the top three lists out
and after that I try to get that answer like this one get
the top one the query is here top
end is here no student allow this one is the context I will
I will show you problem again
it become this one you are AI extend you
are expert in answering the question and
answering this one this one is the
thing that we kept from the vector database
and this one is original question is student can you submit
half an hour and after that I put this
thing into the ln answer this one no student are not
allowed to leave the exam room during the first
30 minutes of the testing period this
one what we get from the from the ih system
okay what what we try to to to ask again the answer is
different a little bit this one is about
ln mechanism that not provide the
same answer with the same prompt okay
okay after this is it your is it you it is your turn to
choose the proper tool for this one
like a
like for the vector database this one you can use your own
vector database the proper one for the
production layer pichorn or the open source or the pg
vector something like this for the lm you
can use any downloadable lm that open sort
in layer llama quinn gem or something else
and then you have to do a big both say that you have to
transform the pdf into the text
and then make the text into the vector you have to find a
proper emitting module by yourself
so even though you can try to bgm3 first okay and then uh
one more thing about this one
if as if you know that you are your hackathon is about the
lego for sorry I need to go to the
this next slide and this slide
okay your work is about a lego that's why uh that's why we
have to go to another database
for example in another case you can use
for the emitting module you can use the image
to be the vector that your your your system can find can
answer with the image or you can change
the sound into the into the vector or so okay for your work
you may choose the knowledge graph
because of the rule is not a normal text you for the for
the law is not you cannot read from the
top to the bottom but the rule is that you can make is
connect one section to another section
and two maybe to another document that's why we have to use
the knowledge graph for solving this
uh for for so internet app like this
one the application and they call the last
circuit model sorry lot of a module here and then they
change the question into the vector
and after that become the vector source and then it's go to
the uh graph database to find
answer from the graph database and then return the answer
to the application and this one right now
many solution they use the old 4j for another thing for the
energy that the q-read term is
the we call the cipher the cipher is that it's similar to
the scl but it's for the graph knowledge
they have solution like this change that the question the
human question into the cipher
to hurry a little bit but you have to
try it yourself okay by using the old 4j
it's become the couplet like this one the document into the
document the document is the graph
the local document to the graph and then
uh the system can curate the graph no drop
down to the base instead of the
vector with an answer to the user
and for the couplet you have because of the the the local
document they have the article inside
let me write a product and item and then some article they
connect to another product or some
sub item connect to another item from different documents
that why you have to link this by
yourself or use the ai module try to link this one but you
have to you have to review the result
but this one is a big big process big human process try to
convert the document into the
to the shank and then link the
similar shank together by using the graph
for example this one document a article a this one uh is it
means this product graph and this
sub item they work this item this one is your task your big
task to make a smart little process
okay another solution is go to the graph like i never try
but uh most of many of my friends in
the e30 they say that okay Microsoft graph is also a good
solution to make that uh the graph like
okay in summary like it's about
this thing uh it's a receiver process
a is about the augment from the question and some answer
and then the generation is that
lm generate the answer to the user but the big task is try
to convert the document into the
knowledge bed this is your task the
system is smart or not it depends on this
the major is this the minor is
lm the major is knowledge bed okay
i think that i use a lot of time okay okay yes the time is
okay okay thank you uh dr latacai
for your sharing and give a basic knowledge and also the
technical knowledge of the lm and the
latacai okay we have one question in the q and a chat box
okay how do you deal with ai that
genuinely follow the answer in the documents versus one
that sometimes just produce a
possible sounding answer sometimes like a
hallucination answer and colleague answer
how do you deal with the ai like that
this is a big problem for the like system
that that's uh the for for the knowledge bed they don't
know the correct answer or not they
know that okay this answer is close to the
question based on the vector they know that
it's it's mathematic similarity they don't know the human
thing okay they don't don't know the
human meaning and then i say that uh if we have the good
enough lm model the good enough lm model
can filter the correct answer to the user this one this i
can say like right now because what
are you does really some more model because a stupid model
they're trying to mix everything
together but when i use this good enough model they try to
filter some uh something else and then
try to keep only the precise answer and keep to the user
okay i think the hackathon now is
we try to build a smart model yeah not stupid model okay
sometimes you you understood that
that the the the participant maybe have to uh fight you in
the model to make small smother okay okay
dr lata chai i think we will join together again after dr
dr chills finish their her presentation
okay uh okay we will continue with uh dr uh professor sheng
chil okay we'll come back again and
okay uh now is uh uh uh last session of
the webinar okay let me introduce the speaker
smart woman professor sheng chil she
she's professor of engineering at mainus
international engineering
co-collec uh her research interests are
center on machine learning and data mining
particularly the applications in data privacy
educational data analytics urban data
modeling and sustainability analysis
molly saidly her work has focused on
the foundation models for ai safety
agentic ai for learning analytics and ai for carbon
accounting reporting and verification
okay now please give a warm welcome to dr sheng chil okay
dr sheng chil the floor is your now
house thank you so much chair um
sorry chair um could i share my slide not sure
so
are you showing um sure the button or the back
sorry the is the sharing button at the bottom it's not
appear not sure really you may you may
out of screen and go back again come back again yeah no no
no not go back from from so much uh
uh out from the screen first and and chatting again
wow the sharing button is in at the
bottom of your screen yeah appear here
do you want me to share for you yeah yes yes yes
all right it happens all the time i
know bob i'm not happy enough time
and for the for the limit question review we will catch up
together after professor shuan finish
okay yeah now yeah okay thanks
so much okay okay go ahead yes
um okay thank you everyone and good afternoon good evening
um so i'm so honored to be here
uh to share for some of my experience um there's all the
sharpness that is here and uh first of
all so the the first speaker already already give quite a
lot of detail so i will have quite a
similar content but i try to avoid like the similar
strengths our first speaker just gave
uh so my focus for this session is actually to discuss
about actually the uh questions that we
just saw um in the q&a sessions is to discuss about the
quality of for lm answers or the ai
system in general and um i would try to give some advices
um to how to control the quality
um from the ai systems in general about nowadays the
general ai systems to give us the
the answers and about how we can human beings to audit
those answers um and just a little bit to
interact a little bit uh background about myself so i'm
from a north international international
engineering college um so i teach in china and i got my phd
uh specialized in data privacy
actually a long time ago from national university of
singapore and uh since then i also worked in
the industry uh for telecom um for telecom standards oh wow
and uh then now i'm working as
the assistant professor in at monose university uh in
ireland so i kind of know like these three
different kind of angles towards the data quality problems
specifically for the data intense systems
or like the ai system in general for quite a few years um
but i surely uh that you know you've
seen the currents um a few years especially the current of
probably three years the one sitting
ai system so i would just want to uh uh highlight that um
so even even for me like the findings
that share the findings from the ai system um based on my
observations changing every day
so today is mostly about many of our
perspectives and the examples we've seen
not just particularly in the legal context but in general
how we design how we design this kind
of ai system to have sort of quality control in terms of
the answers uh jingtong go ahead please
the next slide yeah so uh as i mentioned uh just now so the
focus of this session is about building
responsible ai system i will have a little like more um
discussion about agentic ai specifically
because i know um i've also seen the recordings in previous
sessions that even for the legal experts
that they heard about these words about the
ai agents sort of thing so i will divide it
into the sessions into three parts first of all i have a
discuss about the challenges that the
problems that we have about large mv model
especially when we use it to do the judgment
and the second one is about how how we measure how we
outdid those ariam success in terms of
the judgment the third one is to how to align the larger
model with human principles so as you can
see that there's quite some like technical parts but
there's also quite some of the observations
and the findings from the human from the human centric side
perspective uh so jingtong next slide
please yeah so uh first of all i just want to highlight
that so the problem that this hekerson
tried to solve it's self is a very complex for analyzing
digital trade policy itself um even for
like human beings i mean i'm not from a legal background
but even for the legal experts um
it's very complicated to work flow and the complexity comes
from like three aspects i put here
the first one is the legal purpose and policy life cycle
for digital trade policies so as we can see
the news all the all the times that the policy changing all
the time especially from for the
united states right um and for other people uh like me even
to understand the legal terminologies
it's quite challenging and the policy is changing all the
times and we see the like one policy
came out and later on have the amendment so it's can be
virus and can be very quick so that's one
of the challenge for for us to um design this kind of
system because you need to have this mindset
it's changing all the time it has a life cycle for the
policy so the second one is the policy
it's there in terms of the digital treating is very complex
and it has a regional divergence
um in that sense i mean like for example europe where we
have the gdpr for the privacy uh for the
data privacy we have recently have the eo act um for the
particular to regulate the ai systems
and i've been in singapore i know that um there's like um
in singapore side tend to be on the
strict side right there's quite a lot of rules uh about the
regulations and um from in china in
taiwan believe that all kinds of different kind of policies
um for that what i want to highlight
is that we need to have this kind of mindset even like uh
human things like us to navigate um
among all those policies in different regions it's kind of
challenging instead it's not just for
ai it's it's also for us as humans and the third one is and
and hopefully that you're aware of some
kind of standards are there i put uh one one screenshot
actually from our hacker organization
website um so it's about the pillar 11 uh the standards
already there so pillar 11 in case
you don't know it's relevant to the ict uh boost uh
specifically the trading for the telecom industry
so i used to working as i mentioned i used to working for
the telecom uh sector so i kind of
know that the standards in this zone it's kind of already
provide a lot of details so if you've seen
the analysis that i put the links at the bottom so you can
see that for pillar 11 it's already
like in terms of uh how easy it is like the complexity it's
already an easy one for uh for
the ai system to handle in general the legal side has um
the legal expert will consider pillar 11
is kind of easy area to deal with that's because we have a
lot of standards there uh why for a lot
of other pillars and we have so many pillars here for the
hacker zone it tend to be very complex and
there's no standards and that's kind of uh give us another
layer of complexity that because if
there's no standards and even human beings are even for the
legal experts it's difficult to
navigate all this complexity yeah so this is like the three
challenges i want to just point it out
here it's not just for the ai system but the problem itself
is complicated so the goal of
this hacker zone is of course you leave the workload uh for
the legal experts so it's not
just for a single like uh information
retrieving system uh next slide please
yeah so um i just mentioned about the complexity um and i
really know i'm done with saying like all
kinds of tools and especially nowadays um
i want to point out that especially for the
rest of the years right we've seen the searching interface
i would like to put um um the ai tools
like what we have like chat gbt or you use deep seek or
cloud code all kinds of about all kinds
of out all kind of the ai tools we have it's kind of
interface with search information so if we
think about in this way the search the searching interface
is changing but the complexity is
actually never decreases so the problem is that we have
like all kinds of tools in the past we
have like database right here the postcards and my my
secure and nowadays we have the searching
with the ai interface or chat gbt so the tools we have more
tools doesn't mean that it's effective
and the tools um especially nowadays the ai tools if you
use cloud code those are terminal base
um or codex you you you can experience that the tools
itself has like learning curves um and many
of them are kind of hidden the features are kind of hidden
or like the complexity of the tools
is very well hidden and the third one is the tools have the
floors and we need to be aware of that
before we actually use it and this is very important i will
uh mention it uh a bit in the
in the later the slides about the floors we have especially
for the nowadays uh gen ai system
and just to have this mindset uh it's very
important and can be very helpful when we
actually design because this hackerson is about design ai
system and first one is that the tools
need to be adapted to be useful so this is this hackerson
session this webinar is about how we
adapt them to this particular scenario
for legal contact next next slide please
all right next yeah okay here we go so um
so the good news before we go into the time
to talk the good news are the promise of our arms uh as we
wait uh as we all can't experience it
right so the first while putting the uh uh the first part
is about save time so for our arm
it can process a lot of
documents in parallel if you use charge
with charge gpt very fast i would say and nowadays we have
them to have this summarization retrieval
reference findings all they are all kinds of features you
can use receive um my part of work
time of time and i believe it's also for your workflow and
the second one is it makes searching
and i think it's never in the past but now uh the gen ai
can have the searching more personal on
context aware um if you know how it works like three years
ago the charge gpt and now uh what you
can do uh with charge gpt you can use you can upload the
files right you can ask question just
relevant to that files you you pair the links to your your
serial charge gpt so it makes your
searching uh very personalized very context aware and the
third one is that the error actually is
kind of a new tools we have um to navigating ambiguity um
by that what i meant is if you
use google search right you use keyword searching and you
sometimes you can you can sense that you
need you need to be kind of very precise about to put the
keywords in terms of the searching
uh interface why m can handle this kind of ambiguous
queries and that's quite powerful
and that's it's even like more powerful
when the situation or information is missing
and in the legal context and it happens all the time so in
the beginning of the conversation
and information may be like incomplete or like under
specified and or even conflicting
in this case it's like the policy can complicate each other
but that's not the problem for uh the
um to process information and the last one is also um the
focus of this hacker song is to make the
workflow um uh automated and that's specifically what we
mentioned the recent system we have about
use ai agents it's very powerful because you can uh plan
you can actually specify what you want
the ai agents to do the planning you can ask them to make
decisions use tools and take actions
right with a very limited uh human situation so that's
quite a good advantage of uh nowadays
the cutting edge uh the gni system so next slide please
yeah so however even all those given all those like uh
advantage we have nowadays uh for gni
and i put a screenshot here that at the bottom of your uh
charge gpt interface right highlights
here even since the day one like charge gpt is ai and can
make mistakes and it's out there and i i
and i think i want to be aware of that so um ai can make
mistakes and it's all because of like
uh a different kind of things first thing first reason is
that uh so i think most people aware of
the problem about the frustration um first frustration i
will explain it a little bit later
but that's like um the major problem that we have is uh
with the large end model and it is structure
structure means that we can really not um avoid this
problem because we trained a larger model
in that way and that's why we need to we need to deal with
that right so second one is it's uh
not transparent in terms of the iam itself um like how it
produces answers um it's basically
to us is the black box but nowadays the gen ai um the ai
agent um sides thing can bring our
reasoning step inside so that's kind of a new thing we have
uh but i just want you to be aware
aware of that um so at the root the iam the language um
models are not transparent it's
basically a black box so third one uh is about out of
alignment of the human uh of human
human instructions i i pretty sure that's uh you experience
that it's just your ai don't listen to
you kind of fit one for the fitting mode when we use large
end models so how do you have a feeling
that sometimes a prompt uh it's not very good so the ai
produce uh the ones you you really not
wants it to produce in that way so this kind of the
alignment problems that we have with the
gen i system and the first one and if you're not very
careful if you're using the very
recent very powerful um the systems like codex uh or cloud
code you you will feel um that it is
very costly and this is like all the problems we have with
uh especially nowadays um very modern
cutting edge ai uh ai tools just to bear in mind of all
these problems that we have so next nice
okay so um so i would like to reach in
finally reach into the first part of it to
we've pointed out all the challenges uh um very roughly i
would like to dive into a little a little
bit more details about all these challenges and how we are
we going to mitigate it um in
when we design this kind of system um so the first part i
would like to highlight is the floors um
that we've been mentioned the view slide um in the previous
slides that's the floors we have
in our um particularly i will divide into two parts one the
structure another is inherited
next slide please yeah so um i want uh i
still have kind of the mindset that's uh
about the rm intelligence what we have um i just mentioned
a little bit so but i've seen all the
times there's a common misunderstanding about the rm
intelligence so at the bottom as the first
speaker also mentioned about uh the rm architecture so
basically um how we train uh our um is with this
game like bearing in blank games is essentially to predict
uh the missing words in one sentence
this is how those models begin and but uh we need to be
aware of that this it doesn't mean that
rm can reason by itself um especially the model themselves
so i will put in this you probably
heard about this uh this way of uh this way of describing
rm is another forming of intelligence
and as the first speaker also mentioned its
foundation its foundation is a statistical
so it's all about probability distributions and this kind
of intelligence is not human intelligence
all right the next slide please yeah so um also it's
already mentioned in the previous session
about the transformer um so transformer uh i think i
believe it's also uh just a few years ago so all
the modern uh large-scale model uh based on
the transformer it was uh invented by google
uh a few years ago and um in the previous
session we've already mentioned about the
rm textures and how will i convert all those words into
embeddings into tokens um so this this is a
very nice uh websites which can show you how the
transformer actually uh represent the words into
the vectors and if you're interested you can dive into it
but the idea is here you can say that
the the goal of how we train the transformer is actually
predicting the next words so all all this
like uh the way we treat uh we train the rm is about
feeling blank this this game so that
it's not a human intelligence it's not a form of human
intelligence next slide please
yeah so i won't go to go to details for this slide as um
just now of course people already
mentioned quite a lot about it um but uh i think the
takeaway point here is that inside transformer
that every every word is essentially every token will be
converted into uh uh encoding which is a
kind of the a vector essentially so um this is how i am
digest the information uh next slide please
yeah so uh because of that all the uh all the words um from
the larger mode point of view is
essentially a vector so how the i am like predict the next
words is depending on the similarity as
the first speaker pointed out so this is the word embedding
uh that so we can visualize um in the
high-dimensional space um in the rm inside the n so for
example here the game um for the particle
word game you can find the similarity uh in the n um the
it's latent space and the next the the
nearest word is playing so it's playing games so you can
visualize all the similarity uh with the
tools we have however you can see that all these uh
calculations is very statistical
so the base on the probability
distribution uh next slide please
yeah so um so i probably put very similar um parts as our
first um speaker put there so
one of the very powerful tools we have nowadays is uh is a
rack these are extract information from
documents um so basically if you have the agents so your
queries about a vector database
and so you can retrieve the top k repeats uh inside these
documents so um i put the links
for the open AI cookbook example here if you are interested
to see it in more detail so you can
check the open AI's example here but
roughly uh you can see the diagram here we have so
um for for our average digest all this uh all this system
especially with drag um is you have
this kind of a vector interface vector database um to
project all the informations from the text
from the text space uh to a vector space as we just found
out so it's all about so comparing
similarity as previous slide shows about what they're
inviting is you're comparing the similarity
in the the latent space about this uh
terminology or sentences next slide please
yeah but drag is not just like one uh one step so deep
inside is actually quite a lot of stuff
that the rack system will will handle this uh this document
processing for us so roughly we can
divide into four parts the data preparation uh input
processing retrieval and answer generation
so the reason that um i want you to have an understanding
about this four steps on the hood
is because when we are trying to control the quality of
answers basically we need to optimize
inside these steps like quite a lot of engineering tricks
you can do but this is how we actually
try to make the the answers better and we need to deal with
the those steps within the rack system
the next slide please yeah so first one is the data
preparation um so uh once i want to highlight
that um there's like uh like very practical ways how do how
you actually um do the do the rack
just now we've also mentioned about the graph rack so all
kinds of the rack system you can use
um but i want to point out that the data preparation in
terms of different different tools
for rack is important but also preparing data is also
important one thing you can do is augmenting
the content um you can add a summary you can add like
additional uh metadata for for one particular
document without just expecting them to do all all these
things for there actually it's very
important for preparing the data um so if you say later we
probably can discuss a little
that how we design modern AI agent system you can see like
the five layers of compaction
inside cloud code this kind of the AI agent system uh which
basically like five uh different
granularity in terms of summarization um for the for the
prompt so with that you can already
say that so to preparing to provide additional layer of
summarization for your document for
RM is actually very important um but kind of common
pitfalls is that you just show everything
inside in RM without caring it's having too much like low
quality content or too large too large
documents um to RM is actually uh it will make it perform
much worse um because RM can tend to
like rely on this attention system and have very limited uh
the context windows so don't just show
too long documents to it directly uh next slide please yeah
so the second step is input processing
um and it's basically what we just described how you
project all these contents to embeddings and
you have the knowledge base with your database and how you
how you process this part this time put
some like good practices is you consider how you transform
uh your input to match the content in
the database instead of just don't care about about this
matching problem especially for the
legal kind of sense the very mind that so there's a
different ways to describe the same kind of
legal concept right so we need to uh like have this kind of
mindset we need to have the um
to find to find this kind of matching if you have kind of
mechanical way to do it do it in a
mechanical way uh so common pitfalls we have here is just
don't don't really care just see everything
in the database and hopefully RM can do the work that you
already don't do the work for you uh next
slide please yeah so for retrieval part um and also in the
previous sessions for the hackerson
and most most of time you need to merge like different uh
different kinds of results one is
RM native answers like the RM will actually check the
vector database and have a few uh results
and internally um the RM also rank the results for you so
be aware of that you can tweak the
re-ranking uh the strategy you can have different ways as
RM to rank it and that would um have like
a major impact of the answers you have um from the drug
system and also be aware that you can
integrate the data with some kind of deterministic answers
from relational database so no SQL
database so you can twiggle this together
and to retrieve for your final answers um so
common pitfalls again you are you are you are actually um
you can see that how RM ranked uh
how the rank in the rank system how round
how the result being ranked so if the wrong
if the wrong elements of the document have been ranked very
high of course you will get a wrong
uh next slide please
yeah so uh so far we've already
described like the strategy how how under who the
rack system actually works um but i would like to mention a
little bit uh like one bottleneck
if you use rak in general the rak system is you we've seen
that the rack system actually needs
the vector database to rank all those snippets for you
right and that is basically the bottleneck
that we have uh because even before the AI
agents try to put a reasoning step for you
and if in the this ranking system this rank your rank
strategy is not very good or not very
customized for the legal context and you may miss the
important part and that's why if this kind of
bottom-up uh bottleneck is there right so if the important
information is not there there's no way
that the quality of the answer can be good just to be aware
of this bottleneck there's always this
top k similarity uh comparison there um because as we
mentioned all this word embedding the
similarity comparison is uh statistical it's basically
based on the probability distribution
it's all linked together that's why we've seen that the lm
is different kind of intelligence
next slide please
yeah so i'd like to like highlight some like viral viral
results findings we have from the
AI research uh basically it's a very powerful um nowadays
uh the large model uh some some
researchers found that if you use direct coppers
interaction to handle that um coppers directly
without ranking the ranking in the vector database it's
probably better it's probably better it's
also can save uh can save tokens can save the cost um but
uh this this study is for like the
general context it's not specialized for the legal context
it's just to be aware of that the
coppers um are not really more than natural models not
trained to understand the legal coppers and so
if you use the approach just be cautious about that but
that may overcome the bottleneck
inside inside the rack system yeah next slide please
yeah so this is basically the findings of these studies and
um pretty much the extent that
by directing direct interact with the coppers uh with AI
with tools with particular those tools not
not actually AI tools particularly just those tools to
processing all those uh coppers um
actually it's actually better uh because according to this
study that um for most case it can it can
retrieve the the gold document they put here
like the viral viral important document for
particular answer and that's what i've
just mentioned if in your popk uh similarity
comparison it didn't find the rack system didn't find out
this gold document it's a very important
document basically there's no way that the answers can be
can be good yeah the next slide please
yeah so basically we've just mentioned about um just now
about uh flaws in um judgments especially
for uh structure problem we have for the large end model
because we trained them in that way
so that's pretty much that's not like good good solutions
to handle it you just need to be very
careful um especially when you design the AI system so the
next one i want to highlight is
about the inherited flaws in larger model which actually
inherited from human judgments next
slide please yeah yeah so just now we've um mentioning a
lot of details about larger language
model the model is there uh but recently i've also
mentioned so most people are already become
polarized with the word AI agents that's actually kind of
the system too uh for the very uh
recent a few years of AI research uh i just want to
highlight that AI agents all this kind of design
is actually inspired from psychology uh studies i put this
book here uh which is from denier
um kind of thinking fast so you probably
heard about it so basically one kind of
breakthrough we have for the AI agents why you can feel
especially for the rest in two years
um the the kind general AI is way better than the like a
few years ago when charge we just appear
is because we have involved this kind of really strategy in
terms of short-term memory and
long-term memory and this is inspired by
quite a long time ago uh by denier this uh
this study about human how how human thinking is so um i
think uh the takeaway point is here
just to be aware that that's uh the human thinking is
actually very important when you design
AI agent specifically and um back in i put uh the chart
here back in like the 20th time history
for the researchers in open AI and they've write this thing
about that they've involved this kind
of the design uh inside the AI agents at that time yeah
it's kind of very new yeah next slide please
okay so uh we've mentioned that um about today's topic that
we want you to be aware of that
the inherited floors in our army it's actually a floor in
human judgment uh and this is based on
also psychology study which is the same author uh one of
the other is uh is the same author from the
first book that we shared it's from denier um this is quite
a quite a very recent study in 2021
and basically this is here a psychology book a psychology
uh theory but i would like to uh
to be aware of that uh so the key point here is that even
in human judgments we have noise
there's a the variability in terms of even human judgment
and because of um uh all these language
models that train on our human human uh facts right human
produce the text so it actually
inherited this problem and this kind of variability in
judgment um you can see in AI you can also see
the human judgment so that's why this is something we need
to deal with it and we need also need to
be very kind of aware of it aware of that but you actually
use uh for judgment especially for the
legal context right so most of times um you probably heard
the word as a judge so be very careful
about this this floors actually deep inside from our human
beings and all these things that it's
actually because um even human judgment is the statistical
process and also from psychology
point of view it's actually a very
natural things that we have uh next slide please
yeah so actually in this book uh it describes this problem
that from a human for the human
judgments we cannot really say a human judgment is accurate
because whenever we describe that
um about the judgments people tend to use the word accuracy
um but you heard about the buyers
and that's a like directional arrow so it's actually easy
to to detect but the noise it's
actually very very difficult uh here is based on in this
book that even for human judge
uh for they they've had this study for human judge the kind
of variability and it's very very
different for the same case that so can uh
the same case they put here uh that's the
the the judgment can be in this case of
for the prison years that's based on the
judge sentences um can be from 1.1 years on average but the
highest one can be as high as
15 years so you can see that even even we pull that like
legal expert the judge here the judgments
can be can be very very different um so the kind of bad
news here is that the noise detection is
actually very very difficult so it's not just for the ai
it's just if we want to detect the noise
in human judgment based on this book and this theory it's
very very difficult and next slide
yeah um so given that the conclusion we
have there's always noise inside the judgments
but we don't really want to reach in their own noise
because if we actually can reach their
noise we actually reach the just pure rules and as we know
that's uh in legal system it's not
just about the rules it's a it's about the
interpretation it's about the context the
specific case that so we need to consider so try to balance
it the flexible the flexibility
and the the rules that we don't really want to uh reach in
the zero noise but they say i i don't
even think we can so just be aware of that um no matter you
you actually hire the legal experts
to do the judgment to label your data let's say or you use
the ai agent as a judge that there will
be always this noise uh inside uh but we we need this kind
of flexibility uh in the judgment so
basically it's actually a good thing yeah next slide please
um so we've seen this theory so basically
the point here is that i'm actually inherited
this problem from human judgment um i'm putting this way
instead of ask the questions like how
accurate to you i am judgment can be it's basically a not a
very good question or i i can put in this
being uh it's a wrong question a better way um to put the
question is that so how can we design
uh i am uh judgment system that has a high fidelity how
faithful it is and the good news
is that so we can actually do that we can actually design a
system uh that is faithful that is uh has
a high fidelity even though every time uh that each um each
each time the judgment can be different
so there's a kind of a two kind of things two kind of
things we're discussing one side is accuracy
it's just one number uh basically i i would say that if you
use the arm for judge any single
scores is not reliable because every time it's different
and the arm can give you a different
answer but the good news is that you can
actually control it you can actually put the
design slide and control the fitting part yeah next slide
please so based on these sides i won't
go into details basically you can do a noise or this so the
idea here is that instead of rely on
one um or one um uh agent you can actually have multiple
different kind of um judge the different
kind of personas you can simulate it you can like have this
prompt that arm have different kind of
perspectives and then collectively uh you put the
adjustment together just be aware of those
sub uh what i would call the sub-agents you make sure the
judgment is independent and then you can
narrow kinds this uh disagreement among
the different kind of judge you can merge the
answers together to have a better uh i won't say a better
answer of answer have a higher
fidelity so that's kind of saying how you do the noise
updates based on this book yeah the next uh
and the good news is that this simulation two arm is
actually very cheap you don't need to
hire a legal expert to do it okay next slide please yeah so
there's other things you can use
the tools you can use heat map to see like the disagreement
between different kind of arm judge
or different different kinds of arm agents um so the point
here is that just to be aware that you
can actually audit so the um um judgments for you by
utilizing different multiple agents together
okay next and next slide please
yeah so i think the uh tips for this part is that don't
don't let your arm collapse evidence in
in two scores and i put one one uh number too early uh
that's kind of you try to make the reasoning
or like how the arm can manifest it's really steps as long
as possible right so you can see that how
whether it follows uh the rendering logic you want it to do
and the second one is try to model
this uncertainty because we are dealing with this uh so
this system that you you need to be aware of
that yeah so next slide please yeah so i think i probably
will run uh run over time but and i try i
try to uh explain the next two parts a bit quicker uh so
second one is how to model and audit arm
success in in in in terms of the judgment so just now we
describe the first uh the floors
and how we how we handle it and now if you're using arm
success fully and how to really success
uh next slide please so i would like to use the one study
uh it's also very very new this year
from stanford law school professors from standard law
school so they basically have designed have
this um have this study um that to testing how our whether
whether the arm judgment is any good for
for for the for the law context and the comfort news is
that it's actually way better than i
expected so next next slide please yeah so they basically
have um designed this kind of
this kind of study uh have three steps first of all they
have like uh human baseline they have
like 16 professors from 14 law school from the states and
dealing with 40 representative
office hour questions it's short questions uh for the legal
context um and they do some like blind
judgment about 3000 randomized comparison between the uh
between the um answers which are two um
sorry two ai uh two ai tools they have one is a Gemini 2.5
another one is notebook um with drag
and so they compare the like ai general answers uh to the
human professors the human professor
next one please next slide please yeah so as i mentioned
the result is very comforting and
honestly i'm kind of surprised with
the results overall it mentioned that uh
gimme 2.5 2.5 is the last year this model
have achieving uh more than 75 percent um
when it's comparing to the human structure uh notebook
notebook arm this drug is a bit
less but still very good so you can see in terms of this uh
diagram we have the uh the vingridge
compared to the arm and the instructors um
and you you can see here it's also use the
confidence intervals uh for for calculating all these cases
and for the rates right so just now
we mentioned just to be aware of this this this is the
statistical system you need to have this
kind of uh this kind of uh the statistical
environment to measure how confident we are
to see um how how good is especially to compare to human
beings uh judgment yeah next slide please
yeah so overall even in this paper they also uh like narrow
the uncertainty of the being uh
the vingridge uh but the good news that's not sure is the
good or bad news um so the human
instructors are actually not performance aware when
compared to gimme and notebook for this
particular task so bear in mind this task is uh just for
the very uh representative uh short uh
short questions so the expected answer is also very short
there's not so much complexity inside
so they're just comparing uh those answers from human
instructors and gimme 2.5 and if you know
if you use gimme last year you already know that gimme 2.5
this year's gimme 3 is way better okay
yeah next slide please yeah so they also compared the
harmful rates and that's also quite a surprise
to me and because one of the concerns that uh we should we
should be aware of that is also and can
produce harmful responses and we don't really want that at
all um but i think this study kind of
give us some comforting news that um so we've trained it
today some modern um so we're so it's
time to produce much less uh harmful content yeah so but i
think it's good for your system
actually to monitor it yeah next one please yeah so very
last part i will brief it measure
because it's very very new it's how to align i am these
human principles next one please
oh next slide yeah this is again an AI generate image
actually um i put one example
particularly you probably
heard about it about the cloud code
um um this kind of analysis of cloud code how we design how
how the cloud code was designed
so once the very very very new findings we found that if
you look at the cloud code uh it's actually
from my topic uh in case you don't know um this is very
very uh advanced AI agent and within its
design very surprisingly only 1.6 um is
AI physiologic the last 98 percent is very
deterministic infrastructure it's very engineering and
mechanical way uh to prevent the AI uh not
align with human human human instructions
so as you can see that the human kind of
our kind of principles um human values it's very very
important to design successful like useful
modern AI agents yeah the next slide please yeah um but
like if we want to simplify the
design architecture of cloud code you can you can see it
very clear um to make sure your AI
agents actually align this uh with your principles with
your kind of design steps it's very important
to have these looks inside inside your system so the AI
agents can now can collect the feedback
um based on what you're instructed to do and it can dive
inside the back and to correct it there
and this is what we've learned from the design of cloud
code this make it tremendously way better
uh than many uh than many like the similar kind of AI agent
we have in the past and that's probably
one very important lessons we've we've seen
so this year i mentioned this very very new
studies we have yeah the next slide please
yeah so another thing that we've seen from the AI agents um
from cloud code is that you divide
to isolated context when we design the staff agents as we
just also describe about the multi
agent system so if you can like very clean um do a very
clean separation about those tasks and you
have multiple staff agents that actually can do better um
and you have a parent node or a parent
agents on the top to module these answers they tend to be
have you it tend to give you a better
answers yeah the next slide i will run very quickly to next
a few slides so i won't go to
a lot of details for the other slides but um just want you
to be aware of that just so like uh one
months ago uh i think less than less than one month and
chocolate actually reduced the cloud
for legal plugins you can find it online on github and it's
very very um useful from my point of view
it's give you very like detailed um like um like
instructions how they design AI agents
next slide please i will go over very quickly yes but you
can see that even for an entropic they put
all those uh factings you can see that they have been very
clear matching to AI agents that's the
AI regulatory landscape is moving fast as we just mentioned
about the complexity of the problem
in the in the very beginning of the the slides and it also
mentioned to uh the AI agents that
the one regulation is incredibly ambiguous to say so you
don't don't let AI agent to jump okay and
he asks specifically agents don't paper or answer yeah so
that's all today's uh our our part of
the tutorials all about we need AI agent to handle this
uncertainty yeah i guess i can stop here
because they are all about those um uh cloud code for legal
plugins and you can find all those
details online yeah thank you all for it i think i can stop
here okay professor shears thank you
for your awesome information and chatting okay i think we
are almost in the room are engineers
that's why so many problems so many sure yeah the
techniques yeah yeah okay thank you for for the
idea that try to mitigate the the flaw in LLM and IAG so
many techniques that that maybe the
participant can apply to to the the work okay we have so
many problems i will start from the first
one uh i would like to invite dr latachai to join with uh
professor sheo together okay okay
we will go one by one uh maybe from start from the
professor sheo first what are the best ways
to control LLM stochasticity and the second
question at the same how to make IAG and LLM
less bond deterministic i guess i basically
roughly answer question is uh use my slides
basically there's no past away because today's uh is that
tomorrow's uh yeah yeah yeah and um and
i'm personally using it uh law so i can see like as i
mentioned uh also stanford study right last
year's june like 2.5 and this year's 3.5 it's very very
different and cloud code to be honest
and it's quite expensive so i don't have so much experience
so i i guess if if you look at how uh
that's why i put the entropic that
plug in i personally i've learned a lot
you can see very clear that's how
they can how they specify uh instruct the
don't jump don't don't conclude too fast
yeah so you can we cannot really control the
the distal side of but you can instruct we can interact
with very specifically uh specification
please follow blah blah blah abc and for example i remember
if i have one slide at the bottom i
already jumped uh that part it has been very clear about uh
eoac for example it has been mentioned
to uh in the skiers dot mv files eoac need quite a lot of
interpretation so that means the policy
service ambiguous and i'm not being ambiguous it need a
little it did a lot of more interpretation
right so on purpose um drawing that point i think the
better question for this is we cannot make
a um deterministic because that is uh this thing i've
mentioned you we want to balance the
flexibility to only rules so that that's the thing we want
we want to balance so if we want
the flexibility of ai agents we cannot let it deterministic
so i think the best way is we
we need a kind of embodies principles
the human principles inside those spheres
mcdonk files and to be very specific to to ai agents so
that we can observe that whether the
those agents follow our staff that's the best thing i can i
can imagine but of course you
probably can't have like more creative ways that have
better ways than that yeah i hope that
answered questions yeah okay thank you okay for the second
question i think dr la chai will
catch up this uh very well because you can
handle not only software but hardware also
how should we deal with the lack of
gpu when we are prototyping the solution
by your experience
okay
you you you you get a piece uh sorry yes okay i'm sorry
that okay uh for the gpu is not a big
problem because of that uh we just use
the existing lm that we can download from uh
hacking fest website we use the open source uh the problem
is about uh the other resource only
if we have the five i would say digx spark this is about i
forgot the price we can use until the
120 million billion parameters the one that we can use uh
but but but in this case we don't need
to train the model again because we can use the existing
model that's why we don't need the much
power of the resource which is due to inference mode of the
resource only for that uh the disorder
we needed is about uh uh the pre-processing result that to
try to convert a very very big
document into the windows space or the uh graph database
this one just can answer this
okay thank you and the next session maybe for both the
chills could you please share your
technique to handle a little document that was once
autolytitative but has been partially amended
or withdrawal yeah yeah i think i finally find the button
to share i can share my my very
okay last slide okay the last slide okay yeah yeah that's
how i jumped for this question okay
am i sharing yeah yeah that's right yeah he's one yeah i
just jumped that's actually for this
question uh i never tried but uh and
traffic the plugin have this particular
skiers or the ai agents and you can find the details how
this specify uh it's called the policy
deeper tool so i put some like screenshots the some parts
of the skiers uh markdown files and
you can you can see that that's what i'll just mention
about the last part how to embed the human
principle inside you can see very clearly it tried to stop
the ai agents from uh drop from
i conclude too fast so it's a mention that specifically
before different please answer
does it apply jurisdiction threshold
sectors uh like is uh like just don't he asked to
vice-versa okay the ai agents don't
assume and then it asked the question one
defective dates as uh so this is for amendment i believe so
it asked ai agent to specify very
clearly effective dates enforcement dates often different
and verify policy so the third one is
what's actually new so you can see that this question was
put specifically to drill inside
those laws it's mentioned that identify the delta from what
you already do not the full context of
the law so this is from anotropic i believe they kind of
optimize this prompt a lot with the legal
experts so to me i've learned a lot that's how they do it
it's very specific i would i was hoping
that our lots of students can do these things for
computer-sized students but uh three weeks ago
though i'm trying to fix up this problem for us and it's
good to know that they release it they
release it for free yeah and i think it's very very
generous okay yeah hopefully found the question
yes and uh question number four and five i think almost
similar so i will ask only one question
uh what are the best two our frameworks available today for
domain experts to officially audit
and evaluate llm outputs in a lab by life okay dr lata chai
and uh for social both of you can
share link about the the this this answer yes or give some
discussion about this question
okay dr lata chai do you want to share something for this
question i know but but i forgot the name
can can can i can i say for even if i
forgot the name okay no problem no problem okay
dr she'll about this question the best
truth now i think again we don't know the best
yeah every what participant needs the best everything the
best but know the best you want
i don't really yeah i'm mentioning that the best too and
not i'm not saying the best but uh
overall we've heard entropic is bad yeah but it's quite
quite costly yeah quite costly i think this
hacker so is also we want to build our open source and we
don't want wonder specific models
because today's entropic model is not
models and truck so so bear that in mind i think
the design here is that we need to design the auditing
process inside system instead of rely
everything on the models is there yeah this is uh what i
can put it in this way i think it's better
for this for solving actually yeah for the uh everybody in
the room uh i think uh professor
she will carry your slide to everybody like yeah yeah yeah
okay thank you thank you okay and
uh dr rata chai do you want to share something yeah sorry i
can't find it there are four methods
one is about the faithfulness i forgot the name i'm sorry
it's just read from the book last week
okay i see uh and the other one need to be needed about we
need uh some question and answer for the
experts first and then we can use the rack uh to uh to
check the answer from the rack system by
using the bird or brew or rule or something that we have a
lot yeah and the other one is we can use
the lma just to use the bigger commercial m like a cloud or
gbt or something to check the answer
yeah okay and i forgot the four metrics sorry about that no
problem no problem for all problem
uh i i think i will send you by email both of you and and
you may uh answer them again okay no
problem okay and uh i think this one for malia malia uh you
finish your quota so i go to the other one
okay this one okay i will go to this one uh what do you do
you expect us to build oh i did this
one i'm not sure this uh i just doing this is the question
for for the the the ekaton start
and this one when a law document is withdrawn uh but the
other documents in the purpose still
different or sighted how do you handle those uh the
anchoring references so the system does not
mislead you sir who follow them
quite long question will be answered this way
i think i can have a short answer for it
i yeah yeah i i got that again that we've
saying just now about anchoring how how they specified it
just have another tool to verify
the the reference is missing um if if that's actually a
downrange reference the reference is
if you have another tool mechanically check that probably
the the tools you can ask the AI agents
to check before it uh before it uh give you the conclusion
yeah okay for the from dong li uh at
once llm answers always better than basic than basic models
which level llm should be should we
use i think uh them maybe for the this ekaton
this one
at once llm answers are way better than basic models
yes the uh the bigger model can answer better than the
small model yeah i can say this
and the second question is which level of
llm should we use what kind of level if you
i don't know i don't know maybe the billion uh maybe the
number of parameter for me i i recommend
that for the good answer is about more than 10 billion for
the good answer if you need to use the
tool use that for example you end up to to call the tune i
think that more than 30 billion is better
okay and the other one that uh one i work with that some
thai language sometimes we work with
the typo the gpt always is 120 billion is better for the
typo and we correct every time okay
okay okay this is this question maybe go to over social the
problem that you need class from
kraut for new policy analysis is it only good for agent or
is is also good for api cause to
listening model like the listen gpt models yeah i guess
again i never built such thing for this
hacker so i might there but definitely that we cannot just
rely on cloud cloud code sorry cloud
or entropic the plugin for this hacker so but cloud code
can help us to process the legal documents
to if you recall that on my slide to prepare you to prepare
the data set you put out you put
inside the rug so that's one thing you can do so another
thing is that whether you can use
api cause to do something similar the answer is yes so you
need to check uh the ai uh agent
protocols like google hua agent to agent protocol and to
invite this kind of similar sign
um maybe in your agent cards a description of this agent
and basically you can programmable
you have a programmable way to embed these things if you
use a multi-agent today if you're using
those ai a giant ai framework and hua is one for them yeah
okay i think the time is finished now
so we have the remain to question i think i i will i will
send the question to to both of you and
and for the remain for the remain question and when we give
uh to the the the participant again
after after maybe on monday okay on monday we have uh we
have a wrap-up session for the survivors
of the hackathon participants okay okay the warrior that's
why that's why okay okay thank you
for uh both of you to for sharing today uh
very pleasure from the staff of hackathon
okay thank you for all participants for for the last
session of the opening for everybody
dr vita da okay could you may i say something because yeah
um because uh next week it's going
to be uh the q&a sessions and opportunity for the
participants to ask us the questions that they have
in mind and uh we request participants to submit the
questions that they want to answer before the
sessions uh so if anyone still have uh unclear uh and
anything that you want to know from the
hackathon committee team please send us
the questions by monday morning please
because we will meet again uh monday 7
p.m bank of time so same time as today
i noticed the questions in the q&a that one is coming
addressed to the committee which
i have to answer i will answer these
questions in the next sessions okay okay
okay could you say the close closing but
thank you very much i i really enjoyed the
sessions that are delivered by uh both dr
rata shai and dr shelk uh is very useful and
actually i noticed that the slides that dr
shelk who can have skipped on the entropic
uh quad for legal it's very useful it's already include
many tricks that actually the participants
the participants if they really study that they already
achieved the result and what that what i
can say yeah but if that's clear yeah yeah yeah i actually
cannot share for the permission uh i think
um jin tong could you could you put in the chat box just
not sure about my side i couldn't really
share because of the the main um yeah but anyway yes as
doctor we thought we thought i'd mention that
it's actually found this uh their release
um during the time of my university's team
still working out and like during the haikou so but once
you release i was wondering what we can do
and but i think the good news is that that
is uh as the one the participant mentioned
it's a general purpose general purpose agent we need you
he's to specialize for these contacts
and you still have a lot of rooms to optimize it from even
from a from the side point of view
tons of things that uh the entropic leave the heavy
workload in the legal side for us already
so it makes this hackathon even more interesting that even
if entropic is really into this idea
into this era really that is a very very important area to
solve yeah so we are looking forward for
the all the teams in the shop this and to come up with very
innovative approach to do it and
definitely as doctor because i mentioned the entropic
solved a lot of problems so definitely
check inside and i've highlighted in my slides and you can
see how how much they optimize the
prompt yeah very very very brilliant
like procedures that i'm very i'm very
impressed about applying as euro from entropic yeah but i
guess when they apply these principles
to specific domains and specific countries they will still
have the challenge of applying it to
that specific yeah exactly yeah yeah exactly exactly
there's for for every particular thing
as i mentioned that it's for the general purpose one for
training policies specifically the tools
what kind of the mechanical tools in terms of like existing
tools we try to verify i know that
singapore many teams from singapore uh singapore has the ai
verified tools for general purpose the
ai system and you may can check other other tools um for
this particular uh digital training
regulation hire and the definitely as what we conclude
there's a lot of space is a very
important topic to work on definitely check how entropic do
it in that way and try to customize
in this particular hackerson and personally including me
i've learned a lot from from the
plugins it's just too many they have too many you probably
need some ai to help you to to to
like yeah yeah that's very useful and thank you very much
and uh i hope that we will still
have you indicate in the next step of the
hackathons yeah sure yeah appreciate and
dr rakshan is going to say something like uh okay okay i
just found that uh the framework
cousin is sent into the uh chat box already okay okay thank
you thank you for sharing everything
okay okay see you for the survival
on monday okay bye-bye good night
thank you bye bye bye